-能麻烦你在这里签名吗？ -好的
- Can I get you to sign right here, please? - Okay. Here you go.
-谢谢 -不客气
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
(FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
嗨，  威尔，  你的包裹
Hi, Will. Package for you.
(PEN CLICKING)
我想没有人能在自己的婚礼时想像
I don't think anyone ever imagines on their wedding day
他们会是那46% 没有过幸福快乐的生活族群
be part of the 46% that doesn't live happily ever after.
离婚证书
威尔？
Will?
听说我们拿到了桂格麦片的合约
Just heard we got the Quaker Oats account.
干得好，  你一定很开心吧
Way to go. You must be completely psyched.
话又说回来
Then again,
我从未想过
I never thought I'd spend my days,
我会年复一年的替广告公司卖命
weeks and years working in an advertising agency
每天在这里想该如何哄骗 小孩子们吃某个牌子的麦片
trying to figure out how to get kids to eat Cap'n Crunch instead of Froot Loops.
但星期二与星期五是我最爱的日子
But Tuesdays and Fridays are my favorite days.
可以提早下班 还可以接我女儿玛雅放学
I get out of work early, and I go pick up my daughter, Maya, from school.
找到能搭配一天心情的歌感觉真好
Now, it's a great feeling when you find the right track to go with the day.
我今天可找到了最恰当的歌
And today, I have found the absolute perfect song.
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
婊子们，  她们可亲我的
Bitches, they can kiss my...
是另一首恰当的歌
The other perfect song.
(EVERYDAY PEOPLE PLAYING)
东51街
麦迪逊街
(CAR HORN BLARING)
谢谢
(MOUTHING WORDS) Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
搁浅！急需$$修理太空船 返回欧顿星球
谢谢！
有时不管你多小心的编排曲目
But sometimes, no matter how carefully you plan your playlist,
哈德森梅瑞小学
都找不到一首适合当下状况的歌
there is no right track for what awaits you.
(ALL CLAMORING)
-走了，  走了！ -嘿，  发生什么事？
-Come on, come on! -Hey, what's going on?
威尔，  你知道今天有健康教育课吗？
Will, did you know there was gonna be a sex ed class today?
他们还太小了吧？
Aren't they kind of young?
-对嘛！真是场灾难 -最起码他们开始阅读
-Yeah! It was a total disaster. -At least it got them reading.
有书耶！
There's a book!
“2亿5千万精子射出
"The 250 million sperm are ejaculated
“展开了他们 前往输卵管险恶的旅途！
"and begin their treacherous journey towards the fallopian tubes!
“有一亿万即刻死亡…
"One hundred million are wiped out instantly..."
我要去找玛雅
I'm gonna find Maya.
你还跟爸爸做爱吗？
GlRL: Do you still have sex with Daddy?
-你在说什么？ -还有吗？
-What are you talking about? -Do you?
-我们应该回家谈… -你还有，  对吧？
-You know, we will go home and talk... -You do, don't you?
-我们回家再讨论这个 -我恨你、我恨你！
-We will go home and talk about this. -GlRL: I hate you, I hate you!
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
别拉我！我要弄清楚真相！
Stop pulling on me! I am trying to get to the bottom of something!
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
就是当一个男人将他的生殖器 从睡裤中掏出
Which is when the man removes his penis from his pajamas
并插入一个女人的阴道…
and thrusts it into a woman's vagina...
好的，  但葛莱格老师 并没有说“插入”
Okay, but Mrs. Gallagher didn't actually say "thrust."
有啊
-Yeah. -Oh.
我不懂的是
But what I don't understand,
山米柏根的姐姐说他是个意外
Sammy Boigon's sister said he was an accident.
你怎能不小心的将生殖器插入… 嗨，  路易士
I mean, how do you accidentally thrust a penis into... Hi, Luis.
-嘿 -你怎能不小心的…
-Hey. -How do you accidentally...
停止说“生殖器”与“插入” 就说“嘘嘘的地方”或是“弟弟”
Stop saying "penis" and "thrust." Just say "tinkle part" or "wee-wee."
可爱点的
Something cute.
-解释山米为什么是个意外 -那很复杂
-Explain how Sammy was an accident. -That's complicated.
-生殖器！生殖器 -好了，  够了
-Penis! Penis. -Okay. All right, that's enough.
好的，  他们…
(SIGHING) Okay, they...
他爸又不是踩到香蕉皮
It's not like his dad slipped on a banana peel.
意外是山米的妈妈怀了孕
The accident was that Sammy's mom got pregnant.
他们若不想要小孩为什么要做爱？
If they didn't want a baby, then how come they had sex?
这问题很好
That's a very good question.
可以说他们是在排练
I guess you could say that they were rehearsing.
-我也是意外吗？ -不
-Was I an accident? -No.
-我是，  对吗？ -不
-I was, wasn't I? -No.
你绝对是故意的 我非常清楚发生了什么事
You were completely and totally on purpose. I knew exactly what I was getting into.
(SIGHS)
易碎品 请小心搬运
我想你该跟我说你与我妈的事
I think you should tell me the story of you and my mom.
你为什么一直称她为“我妈”？ 好像我从未见过她似的
Why do you keep saying "my mom" like I've never met her?
因为你要离婚了
Well, because now that you're getting divorced,
所以她是我的，  不是你的
she's mine, not yours.
-是这样吗？ -告诉我你们的事
-Is that so? -Tell me how it happened.
真实的故事，  不是什么 “我们相遇并相恋
And the real story, not the, "Oh, we met, we fell in love,
“然后决定用我们的爱
"and we decided to take all that love
“建立一个家庭并生下你”
"and make a family, and that's how we made you."
你知道吗？我将会告诉你 我跟你妈相识的
You know something? I'm gonna tell you the real, true story
来龙去脉
of how me and your mother met.
-等我长大时 -没错
-When I'm old enough. -Yep.
-我知道爱情不是童话 -真的？
-Look. I know love isn't a fairytale. -Really?
真的
Really.
你在认识她之前有别的女友吗？
Did you have another girlfriend before you met her?
(CHUCKLES)
拜托，  跟我说实情
Come on, tell me the truth.
(SIGHS)
我有两个固定的女友
I had two serious girlfriends.
还有一些在交往的女人
And then some other, a smattering of other women that I dated.
你知道
You know.
什么？
What?
男生的荡妇叫什么？
What's the boy word for slut?
他们还没有想到那名词 但我相信他们正在想
They still haven't come up with one yet, but I'm sure they're working on it.
你这礼拜吃素吗？
You a vegetarian this week or not?
-嗯，  吃素 -好
-Yeah, I am. -Great.
我猜你也不是她的初恋
I'm guessing you weren't her first boyfriend.
他可能是个书呆子或是很凶
Maybe it was some nerdy guy, or maybe he was mean.
或许
Or maybe
(FAUCET RUNNING)
你们当了很久的朋友
you were friends for the longest time,
然后正当你准备将你的生殖器
and then just when you were about to put your penis
放进另一个女人的阴道时…
into somebody else’s vagina...
晚安，玛雅
Okay. Good night, Maya.
…你发现妈才是你的至爱！
...you realized Mom was the only one for you!
睡觉时间！
Bedtime!
你还是得告诉我你为何爱上她
You still have to tell me the story of why you fell in love with her.
我爱上她是因为她很聪明 漂亮又好玩
I fell in love with her because she was smart and beautiful and fun.
那她现在就又蠢又丑又无聊了吗？
So now she's stupid and ugly and boring?
-当然不 -那问题出在哪？
-Of course not. -Then what's the problem?
-很复杂，玛雅 -你什么都很复杂
-It's complicated, Maya. -Everything with you is so complicated.
我想若是你跟我说了那故事 你就不会觉得一切都如此复杂了
I bet that if you just told me the story, you'd realize that it's not complicated at all.
你就是爱她
That you just love her.
我知道这事对你来说很艰难 但你在想什么？
I know this is tough for you, but what are you thinking?
你认为故事说完后就没事了吗？
That I'm gonna tell you this story and it's gonna make everything better?
人生没那么简单
It doesn't work that way.
也许是，  也许不 跟我讲了后我们就知道了
Maybe it does, maybe it doesn't. Tell me and we'll find out.
不，  玩完了，  该睡觉了
No. Game over. It's time for bed.
不，  不是睡觉的时候 是你该跟我说那故事的时候
No, it's not time for bed! It's time for you to tell me the story!
-玛雅 -我需要知道！
-Maya. -I need to know!
我需要知道
I need to know.
好啦！好啦！
Fine! Fine!
我跟你说
I'm gonna tell you the story,
-但不告诉你哪个是你妈 -好
-but I'm not telling you who your mom is. -Fine.
你得自己弄清楚
You're just gonna have to figure it out for yourself.
-好 -我还会用化名
-Good. -And I'm changing all the names
并更换一些细节 不过这是我现在才想到的
and some of the facts, but I just decided that right now.
-然后我们再来看看你有多聪明 -我喜欢，  像是爱情兼悬疑故事
-And then we'll see how smart you are. -I like it. It's like a love story/mystery.
-很好，  听来不错，  准备好了吗？ -没
-Great. Sounds good. You ready? -No.
没
No.
-慢慢来 -我会的
-Take your time. -I will.
-我知道你会 -你来这里
-I know you will. -You go here.
-公主枕头？ -谢谢
-Princess pillow? -Thank you.
-没问题 -好
-You bet. -Okay.
(SIGHS)
我好了
I'm ready.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time,
在还没有电邮、手机与真人秀之前
before e-mails and cell phones and reality television shows,
美国青年民主党员
确切来说是1992年 在威斯康辛州的一个叫麦迪逊的小镇
in 1992 to be exact, in a little town called Madison, Wisconsin,
住了位名叫威廉海约的青年
there lived a young man named William Hayes.
-嘿，  威尔，老兄，  新年快乐 -嘿，  你也是
-Hey, Will, man, Happy New Year. -Hey, yeah, you, too.
这名青年深爱著他在大学的女友
Now, this young man was deeply, deeply in love with his college sweetheart.
就叫她…
Let's call her...
-艾蜜莉！ -艾蜜莉！
-Emily! -Emily!
艾蜜莉！
Emily!
-嘿 -嗨
-Hey. -Hi.
10、9、8…
ALL: Ten, nine, eight...
嘿，猜猜再过4秒后 谁会是全世界最幸福的人？
Hey, guess who's gonna be the luckiest guy on planet Earth in about four seconds?
你
You.
…2、1！
ALL: ...two, one!
新年快乐！
Happy New Year!
他们是金童玉女
They were a perfect couple.
除了要真正了解这青年
Except to really understand how this young man
最后为何娶了你母亲 你必须要先知道
ended up marrying your mother, you'll also need to know
他怀抱著一个又大 又令人难为情的梦想
that he had a very big, incredibly embarrassing dream.
请起立
All rise
向美国总统致敬
for the President of the United States of America,
威廉
William
马修
Matthew
海约
Hayes.
你想当总统吗？
(CHUCKLING) You wanted to be President?
我只是，  我不懂你为何要在纽约 帮柯林顿做事
I'm just, I don't understand why you have to work for Clinton in New York.
你为何不能在麦迪逊替他卖命呢？
Why can't you just work for him in Madison?
因为这不需要人，  他们需要我去纽约
Well, because they don't need me here. They need me in New York.
他们需要他，  小艾，  威尔太帕 我不敢相信你要让他去
They need him, Em. Will's the man. I can't believe you're letting him go.
你没听说过纽约的女孩子吗？
I mean, don't you know about New York girls?
除了长相超辣之外 她们完全不介意一夜情
Besides being incredibly hot, they have no problem with casual sex,
我可是非常赞同
which by the way, I totally respect.
-万一给查理说中了呢？ -查理从来没说对过
-What if Charlie’s right? -Charlie’s never right.
-他是个智障 -我很担心纽约会改变你
-He's functionally retarded. -I am worried New York's gonna change you.
-改变也可能是好的 -如果我们一起改变
-Change can be good. -If we change together.
那我们就一起改变啊
So, we'll change together.
好吗？不过就去纽约两个月 我一下就回来了
Okay? It's two months in New York. I'll be back before you know it.
况且，  我们还有计划，  对吗？
Besides, we have a plan, right?
另一件事是我不敢相信 你竟然敢把艾蜜莉跟我留在这
The other thing I can't believe is that you'd risk Ieaving Emily here with me,
我得实说，  我对你一直有好感…
'cause I gotta tell you, I've always had a thing for you...
况且我完全没有道德可言
And I have absolutely no scruples.
等等！我差点忘了 你要把这个给夏曼
Wait! I almost forgot. You have to give this to Summer.
她是我在纽约唯一认识的女生
She's the only girl I know in New York.
-我希望你会会她 -夏曼哈德尼？
-I want you to meet her. -Summer Hartley?
-对 -她的名字？
-Yes. Yes. -That's her name?
她是我在剑桥当交换学生时认识的
She was on my exchange program at Cambridge,
所有的男生都想跟她上床 你看到她时或许也会这么想吧
and all the guys wanted to sleep with her, and you probably will, too.
或许你该寄给她
Maybe you should mail it to her.
-可能好些 -不
-That might be a better idea. -No.
是什么？
What is it?
一样我很久以前就该给她的东西
Something I should have sent her a long time ago.
我爱你，  威廉海约
I love you, William Hayes.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
好吧，  快走、快走，  好好做
Okay. Go, go, go. Go be your brilliant self.
艾蜜莉听来像是个好妈妈
Emily sounds like she would make a good mom.
-我只是不确定她是不是我妈 -为什么？
-I just don't know if she's my mom. - Why not?
大家都知道
Everyone knows that the girlfriend
在故事最初的女朋友一定会被甩
in the beginning of the story always gets dumped.
这表示夏曼哈德尼可能是我妈
Which means maybe Summer Hartley is my mother.
我永远忘不了那天
I'll never forget that day.
我来到了梦寐以求的城市
There I was, arriving in the city I always dreamed about
来为我深信的竞选活动尽一份力
to work on a campaign that I believed in with all of my heart.
更何况，  我深信在几个小时后
And on top of that, I was positive that in just a few hours,
活动的负责人就会发现 我有多么的优秀
the campaign manager would realize how brilliant I was.
然后我将负责写讲稿
And then I'd be writing speeches,
然后负责研发战略，  不久后…
and then I'd be coming up with strategy, and before long...
威尔海约？
GARETH: Will Hayes?
-嘿，  盖瑞斯亨德逊 -你是盖瑞斯
-Hey. Gareth Henderson. -You're Gareth.
-你好吗？ -幸会，  我们走吧，  海约
-Hey, how are you? -Nice to meet you. We're walking, Hayes.
我带了我的履历表还有一些 我帮史威尼议员写的演讲
I brought my C.V. and a sample of some speeches I wrote for Congressman Sweeney.
很好，  我在空档时 一定会好好拜读一番
Fantastic. I cannot wait to peruse these in my abundant spare time.
在那之前，  这些咖啡与培果订单
In the meantime, here's a sample of the coffee and bagel order
需要补齐
I'll need filled immediately.
等等！
Wait!
你要我去买咖啡？
You want me to get coffee?
每人都有某时期要买咖啡 现在轮到你了，  快点
At some point in our lives, we all get coffee. Your time's now. Come on.
海约，  我们还在走
We're still walking, Hayes.
咖啡早上十点要到 不然亚瑟会杀了我！
Have the coffee here by 10:00, or Arthur's gonna kill me!
就表示我就得杀了你 我以前可是下过手，  海约
That means I'm gonna have to kill you. I've killed before, Hayes.
-你应该要知道 -这是什么？
-You should know that. -What is this?
这是手机
That is a cellular telephone
让我可随时随地为了任何事找到你
so I can get a hold of you wherever, whenever, for whatever.
-谁帮我拿些阿斯匹灵好吗？ -小心点！
-Can somebody get me an aspirin, please? -Watch it!
欢迎你加入，  海约！
Glad to have you aboard, Hayes!
-嗨 -什么？嗨
-Hi. -What? Hi.
4周后，  纽约的选民
ARTHUR: Four weeks from now, voters of New York State
将选出下一届的民主党总统候选人
will select their next Democratic nominee for President.
若比尔柯林顿赢了
Now, if Bill Clinton wins,
我要你们知道那将是
I want you to all understand that it's gonna be as a direct result
在座每一个人的心血所产生的结果
of the commitment and the energy of every person in this room.
我是说真的，  那是事实
And I mean that. That's just a fact.
这工作就是如此重要
Now, that's how important the work is.
在座的每一位…
That each and every one of you is...
(WILLIAM SCREAMS)
(CRASHING)
我在这做什么？
(SHOUTING) What am I doing here?
新来的
It's the new guy.
-嘿 -嘿，  那是送卫生纸的人吗？
-Hey. -Hey, is that the toilet paper guy?
-可以给我一包摩利红烟吗？ -三块两毛五
-Can I get a pack of Morley Red, please? -3.25.
三块两毛五？ 在威州麦迪逊才卖两块一毛五
3.25? These are $2.15 in Madison, Wisconsin.
那你就回麦迪逊啊
So go back to Madison.
-记得写信 -没错，  记得要写信
-Don't forget to write. -That's right. Don't forget to write.
等等！停止！
Hold it! Stop. Stop right there!
你曾抽烟？
You smoked?
不，  是啦
No. Yeah.
但我本来不打算跟你说的
But I didn't mean to tell you that.
听著，  我那时很年轻并很蠢 我很多年没抽了
Listen. I was young, and I was stupid, and I haven't smoked in years.
我发誓
I promise you.
还有什么应该跟我说的？
Is there anything else you should tell me?
大概没有吧
Probably not.
-能帮我影印十份吗？ -跟那叠放在一起
-Can I get 10 copies? -Put them on the pile.
不，  是亚瑟要的 我15分钟前就该拿到了
No, they're for Arthur. I need them like, 15 minutes ago.
你若不介意的话…
So if you wouldn’t mind...
你是送卫生纸的那家伙
You're the toilet paper guy.
-慢著，  那是谁？ -那是艾波
Wait. Who's that?  That's April.
没错，  我正是送卫生纸的那家伙
Yes. I am, in fact, the toilet paper guy,
但你也可称我为送培果与咖啡的家伙
but feel free to call me the bagel-and-coffee guy.
会计部的陶德叫我克莉丝朵 我很确信那是女生的名字
Or Todd in Accounting calls me Crystal, which I'm pretty sure is a girl’s name.
-几份？ -请印十份
-How many copies? -Ten. Please.
-这些？ -对，  两面都要
-These? -Yeah, both of those.
你为什么会支持柯林顿？
What made you become a Bill Clinton supporter?
我没有啊，  我是支薪的，  一小时12块
I'm not. This is a money gig. I get paid 12 an hour,
比看小孩好赚多了 我当褓母已当到腻了
which is better than babysitting, which is what I've been doing way too much of.
你是民主党员吗？
You're a Democrat, right?
人为什么非得是 民主党或共和党员才行呢？
Why does everyone have to be a Democrat or a Republican?
我连影印机都搞不定
I'm struggling with the copy machine.
等等，  你是独立党的？
No, hold on. You're an Independent, aren't you?
我什么都不是 我为什么一定要跟从某个党派？
I am nothing. Why am I obligated to be something?
我为什么要对每件事都有立场？
Why do I have to have an opinion about everything anyway?
说真的，  我对飞弹系统
I mean, really, what do I know about missile systems
或社会安全或税法又了解多少？
or Social Security, or the tax code?
那民权与女权呢？
What about civil rights or women's rights?
女人堕胎的权力呢？这件事呢？
A woman's right to do what she wants with her body? What about that?
我主导我的身体
I do what I want with my body.
那样太冷漠了
That's apathetic.
-我才不冷漠 -你是
-I'm not apathetic. -Yes, you are.
我没有，  我只知道 你在卖命的那群蠢蛋
I'm not. I just know that these bozos you're working for,
除了他们自己的野心之外 什么都不在乎
they don't care about anything more than their own ambitions.
才不是那样
That's absolutely not true.
你真的觉得比尔柯林顿这家伙 能做什么大改变吗？
You think this guy, Bill Clinton, is gonna make a huge difference?
-我相信 -他将做的都是无可避免的
-I do. -He's gonna do what's already inevitable.
-你错就错在这 -别逼我用钉书机钉你的头！
-Okay, that's where you're wrong. -Don't make me staple your head!
你错了，  他将改善黑人权益
You're wrong. He's gonna make a difference with African Americans.
也将改善妇女权益，  他了解女性
He's gonna make a difference with women. He gets women.
-天啊 -我是说，  看看他在阿肯色的政迹
-My God. -I mean, look at his record in Arkansas.
去读一下他的保健计划 去读一下他的教育计划
Read his plans on health care. Read his plans on education.
-好吧，  别读，  嗯 -天啊，  真抱歉
-Okay, or don't. You know, yeah. -Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
-嗯，抱歉 -我睡著了
-Yeah, I'm sorry. -I just fell asleep.
-很抱歉 -没关系
-I'm really sorry. -Yeah. That's fine.
醒来时就是个新美国了
Wake up to a new America.
-我相信你 -这次交谈真有趣
-I believe you. -This has been really interesting.
-很好，  你说服了我，  你是无党籍 -我无党籍
-Fine. You convinced me. You're nothing. -I'm nothing.
我在诸位前再度重申…
FLOWERS ON TV: So I'm here to repeat in front of all of you...
嘿！听著！大家快看！
Hey! Listen up! Look up, everybody!
珍妮佛芙劳尔斯 号称柯林顿情妇
是的，  我当了 比尔柯林顿的情妇超达12年
Yes, I was Bill Clinton's lover for 12 years.
嘿，  谁开大声点
Hey, somebody turn it up.
过去的两年中，  我为了保护他 而对媒体隐瞒我俩的关系
For the past two years, I have lied to the press about our relationship to protect him.
事实上，  我爱过他
The truth is, I loved him.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
但他现在要我否认
Now he tells me to deny it.
我厌倦了这所有的欺瞒与谎言
Well, I'm sick of all of the deceit, and I'm sick of all of the lies.
你倒是说对了一点 他的确很了解女人
Well, you're right about one thing. He certainly gets women.
-这次谈话很有趣 -再见，卫生纸家伙
-This has been fun. Yeah. -(LAUGHING) Bye, toilet paper guy.
再见，  影印小妹
Bye, copy girl.
天啊，  真没完没了
Oh, my God. It never ends.
他们就一直不停的重复播放
They just keep playing it over and over and over again.
-会过去的 -是喔
- It's gonna bIow over. -Right.
人们不在乎这种事情
PeopIe don't really care about this stuff.
-这是重点 -我不懂的是
-That's the thing. -What I don't understand,
我听说布希也有情妇
I've heard Bush has a mistress.
大家都在讨论 为什么他可以而柯林顿就不行？
Everybody's talking about it, so why is it okay for him and not for Clinton?
她很随便
She's trashy.
光看到她的发型 就足以用此来攻击柯林顿
I mean, her hair alone is enough reason to go after Clinton.
有什么大不了的 每个人都有弱点，  了吗？
Big deal. Everyone has their weaknesses, you know?
那些顶著假指甲，  肉肉的红发女人？
Those chubby redheads with the long, fake fingernails?
-老子就喜欢这种 -好恶喔
-That's what Daddy likes. -That's just nasty.
盖瑞斯，  你有够讨厌
Gareth, you are unfailingly repugnant.
嘿，  太巧了，  我最喜欢会说 “有够讨厌”的女人
Hey. That is a coincidence. I love women that say "unfailingly repugnant."
知道我喜欢哪类的吗？
You know what I love?
我喜欢棕色长发 并戴著粗框眼镜的女人
I love long-haired brunettes with horn-rimmed glasses.
我也不知道为什么 她们就像是我的死穴
I have no idea why. They're like kryptonite to me.
我也是
I got that one, too.
我抗拒不了会被我吸引的男人
I got a thing for guys who've got a thing for me.
你或许该看看心理医生，  我要举杯
You might wanna look at that. I'm gonna propose a toast.
没问题
I am fine with that.
-敬比尔与他的弱点 -对
-To Bill and his weaknesses. -Yes.
-敬比尔 -敬比尔
-To Bill. -To Bill.
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
喂？
Hello?
嘿！是我！
Hey! It's me!
-是艾蜜莉吗？ -是艾蜜莉吗？
-Is that Emily? -Is that Emily?
-嗨，  艾蜜莉！ -嗨，  艾蜜莉！
-Hi, Emily! -Hi, Emily!
怎么那么吵？
What's all that noise?
没什么，  我的几个白痴同事在取笑我
Nothing. That's just a couple of idiots I work with making fun of me
因为他们没有一生至爱的漂亮女友
because they don't have a beautiful girlfriend that they're eternally devoted to!
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
你好美
You're beautiful.
-你发情了 -可能被你说中了
-You're horny. -You might be right.
(EMILY LAUGHING)
艾蜜莉？到纽约来
Emily? Come to New York.
你会很喜欢的 这里的活力与人群真的很棒
You'll love it here. It's the energy, the people. It's amazing.
等等，  你刚刚说“活力”吗？ 威尔，  你刚刚没说“活力”吧？
Whoa, did you just say "energy"? Will, you did not just say "energy."
什么？
What?
你不会回来了
You're never coming back.
嘿，  拜托 我只是想要你过来度一个周末
Hey, come on, now. I just want you to come for a weekend.
你说得对，抱歉
You're right. I'm sorry.
你有联络到夏曼吗？
Did you call Summer?
没有，  我留了言，  她没有回我
No. I left her a message. She didn't get back to me.
嘿，  你还好吗？
Hey. You okay?
嗯，  只是很寂寞
Yeah. I'm just really lonely here,
我想死你了，  真的很难熬
and I miss you like crazy, and it's really hard.
嗯，  我懂你的意思
Yeah. I know what you mean.
-你怎么还没睡？ -麦克迈先生
-Hey. What are you doing up? - Mr. McCormack.
拜托，  你已经盯著那包裹一个礼拜了
Come on, you've been staring at that package for about a week now.
你今晚怎么样？看来很成功
How was the rest of your evening? Successful, I take it.
老天，  我惨了，  我爱上这女孩了！
Oh, my goodness. I'm in big trouble. I love this girl!
那通常是件好事
You know, that's usually a good thing.
要当第一位黑人总统就已经够困难了
It's hard enough to get elected the first black President
真的不需要在就职典礼时 还搂著茱莉亚罗勃兹
without having Julia Roberts on your arm at the inauguration.
你的想像力真丰富，  小罗
That is an impressive mental leap, Russ,
从一夜情跳到总统宣誓
going from a one-night stand to being sworn in as President.
打开它
Open it.
我知道你很想知道里面是什么
I know you're dying to know what's inside.
光是她的名字，  夏曼哈德尼 就让我快…
Just her name alone, Summer Hartley, is driving me...
你看！这边破掉了！我看到了
Look it! You got a tear right there! I see it.
快点，  你可以的
Come on through. You can do it.
谢谢你，  对
Thank you. Yes.
-是本日记 -老天，  我看看
-It's a diary. -Sweet Jesus. Let me see.
不！住手，  我们不能读这本日记
No! Stop! Stop right there. We're not gonna read this. We can't.
“男子宿舍在对面 窗口正对著我们的窗户
"The boys' dorm is across the quad, their windows visible from ours.
“晚上又热又黏
"The evenings are hot and sticky.
“我们都衣衫不整的 假装对面的男生看不到我们
"We are all half-dressed, pretending we can't be seen by the boys.
“有些女孩很大胆，  我的新朋友
"Some of us are bold. My new friend
“艾蜜莉人很好
"Emily is sweet
“并对这一切感到难为情 她永远都在等我下一步会怎么做”
"and embarrassed by it all, always waiting to see what I will do."
别停啊！这很劲爆，  你刚念到哪？好
Don't stop! This is good stuff. Where were you? Okay.
“这是我们的最后一晚 已经计划了好几天
"It's our last night, and the plan has been in place for days.
“艾蜜莉与我是最后离开的
"Emily and I are the last to leave,
“当我们走到楼梯口时 我抓住了艾蜜莉的手腕
"and as we reach the stairs, I grab Emily firmly by her wrist.
“她抬头以期盼的眼光看著我 我知道接下来将发生什么事”
"She looks up at me expectantly and I know what will happen next."
-你知道吗？ -我想我知道吧
-Do you? -I think I have a pretty good idea.
我的天！
Oh, my goodness!
你在干嘛？这可是好料的，老兄！
What are you doing? This is good stuff, man!
等等
Wait a minute.
是你的艾蜜莉吗？
Is that your Emily?
晚安，  罗素！
Good night, Russell!
她好狂野！
She is a freak!
把照片放回去！
Put the picture back!
哗
Wow.
-谁啊？ -我是威尔海约，  之前打过电话
-HAMPTON: Who is it? -Will Hayes. I called earlier.
(CLEARS THROAT)
你是耶和华见证会的？
HAMPTON: You a Jehovah's Witness?
不
No.
老天，  你好高
Christ, you're tall.
(LATCH UNLOCKING)
嘿
Hi.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON PHONOGRAPH)
-进来 -好
-Come in. -Okay.
把门关上
CIose the door behind you.
锁起来！
HAMPTON: Lock it!
夏曼要你等等 她会回来，要你等一下
Summer said to hang tight. She'll be back. She wants you to wait.
-你手上拿著什么？ -不知道，  你是夏曼的父亲吗？
-What do you got in there? -I don't know. Are you Summer's father?
对，  我是她的老子
Yeah. I'm her daddy.
-喝酒吗？ -不，  有点太早了
-Drink? -No. No. It's a little early for me.
早，  你才刚来不久，  是吗？
Early. You're fresh off the boat, aren't you?
谈谈你自己吧，现在怎么样？ 有什么理想？
So tell me about yourself. What's your deal? What do you aspire to?
有什么梦想吗？你喜欢些什么？
What are your dreams? What are your fancies?
长大后想要做什么？
What do you want to be when you grow up?
-坐下！ -好
-Sit down! -Okay.
你在哪里高就？你…
What do you do now? You...
等等，  让我猜，  你帮你爸做事
Wait, don't tell me. You work for your daddy.
-不 -不，  别跟我说！
-No. -No, don't tell me!
华尔街，  不！
Wall Street. No!
你在上城某家大律师所拍马屁
You kiss ass to some fancy uptown law firm.
-其实… -不！我放弃，  你是做什么的？
-Actually... -No! I give up. What do you do?
我帮比尔柯林顿做事，  他在竞选总统
I'm working for Bill Clinton. He's running for President.
不是吧
No.
我知道比尔柯林顿是谁
I know who Bill Clinton is.
事实上，  我比比尔柯林顿他妈 还要了解他
Yeah, in fact, I know more about Bill Clinton than his own mother.
-真的？ -嗯
-Really? -Yep.
-你在哪高就？ -我在哪高就？
-What do you do? -What do I do?
我喝酒！
I drink!
喝！
Drink!
当个男人
Be a man.
就是这样！好多了吧？
There you go! Isn’t that better?
吞下它！
Swallow!
跟我谈谈比尔柯林顿
So tell me about Bill Clinton.
嘿，  醒醒
Hey. Wake up.
你要阿斯匹灵吗？
You want some aspirin?
-你一定是威尔 -嗨
-You must be Will. -Hi.
看来你灌醉了我男朋友
I see you drank my boyfriend under the table.
-他不是你爸？ -他这样跟你说的吗？
- He's not your father? -(CHUCKLES) Is that what he told you?
Hmm.
他是我的论文指导
He's my thesis advisor.
Oh.
他还说了什么？
What else did he tell you?
他教我如何做一个真男人，  而不是
He was telling me how to be a real man, as opposed to the sort of
-像我现在这小毛头样 -你学到了什么？
-boy-man I seem to be. -Did you learn anything?
嗯，要喝很多酒
Yeah, there's a lot of drinking involved.
还有骂脏话与干架
AIso cursing and fighting.
-性？ -对
-Sex? -Yes.
不过我们真男人不会用那个字眼
Although that's not what we real men call it.
那你们会怎么说？
What do you call it?
我有东西要给你 是艾蜜莉要我转交的
I have something for you. This is from Emily.
-我好久没跟她联络了 -我们今年秋天就要同居
-Haven't talked to her in ages. -We'll be moving in together in the fall.
Uh-huh.
拜托！老爸
Oh, please! Daddy.
(LAUGHING)
拜托！不
Oh, come on! No.
这是…
Oh, this is...
她等待著我的回应而我屈服了 我吻了她
你看过了吗？
Did you read this?
没有
I didn't.
-我看了一页 -一页
-I read a page. -A page.
-最多两页 -两页？
-Two pages at the most. -Two?
你与艾蜜莉接吻与互抚的那段
And the part about you and Emily touching each other and kissing.
-那段，  嗯 -很细致的描述，  像是身入其境
-Oh! That part, yeah. -Incredibly descriptive. I felt like I was there.
你的文笔很好，  我是说…
You're a great writer. I mean...
我想这应该给你，  你寂寞时可以看看
I think you should keep it. You should read it when you're lonely.
-我不能，  是你的日记，  我不能留著 -不，  真的，  我不需要它
-I can't. It's your diary, so I can't do that. -No, really, really. I just, I don't need it.
我已经背起来了，  我就留在桌上
I've already got it memorized, so I'll just leave it on the table.
原版的你就留著吧 这样对我来说比较好
Keep a hard copy. That might be nice for me.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
我很好奇艾蜜莉为何要你来给我
I wonder why Emily gave it to you to give to me.
Hmm.
汉普顿？
Hampton?
-汉普顿？ -你要加入我们吗？
-Hampton? -Are you gonna join us?
他是汉普顿罗斯，  知名作家
That's Hampton Roth. He's an incredible writer.
-他那本关于麦高文竞选活动的书… -是啊
-His book on the McGovern campaign is... -Yeah.
-你… -是啊，  我们做了
-You... -Yeah. We do.
听著，  你有跟年过六十的人 上床过吗？
Look, have you ever actually had sex with a sexagenarian?
-我没有 -那你就不该批判
-I haven't. -Well, then you shouldn't really judge.
我没有在批判，  你看你
Well, actually, I'm not judging. Look at you.
你很美、很世故 又是个很有才华的作家
You're beautiful. You're sophisticated. You're a very talented writer.
谢谢
Thank you.
能满足你这样的女人的人一定是个…
I mean, to please a woman like you, it would obviously take a...
-真男人 -正是
-Real man. -Exactly.
-很难成为他的对手 -除非你是竞争心很强的那种人
-Hard to compete with that. -Well, unless you're the competitive type.
-嗯，  幸会 -嗯，  也很高兴认识你
-Yep, nice to meet you. -Yeah, it was great meeting you, too.
我真的很抱歉拿了…
I feel horrible about taking the...
抱歉
Sorry.
我只是好奇
I was just curious.
汉普顿鼓励我去发掘我的好奇心
Hampton encourages me to cultivate my curiosity.
他说这对成为一名好记者非常重要
He says it's the key to being a good journalist.
是啊
Yeah.
夏曼！老子饿了！
HAMPTON: Summer! Daddy's hungry!
说曹操，  曹操到，  我得进去了
-Speak of the devil. Better go. Yeah. -Hmm.
你他妈的在哪？
HAMPTON: Where the hell are you?
-好，  再见 -再见
-Okay, bye. -Bye.
嗯，  有空打个电话来 我们可以一起出去吃晚餐
Yeah, give us a call sometime. We should all go out for dinner.
我…好啊，  晚餐听来不错
I'd... Yeah, I'd love dinner.
-嗯 -嘿！
-Yeah. -HAMPTON: Hey!
-你要打给她吗？ -你疯了吗？
-Are you gonna call her? -Are you insane?
-你要怎么做呢？ -我要怎么做？
-Well, what are you gonna do? -What am I gonna do?
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
我要专注在目标上 艾蜜莉与我是有未来的，  我们有计划
I'm gonna keep my eye on the ball. Emily and I have a future. We have a plan.
现在可能还包括3P
Which may involve some type of threesome now.
若那老家伙还在的话就是4P了
Or foursome if that old dude is still in the picture.
你这是在帮倒忙
You're not helping.
我根本不该打开那本日记的 它就像是个潘朵拉又辣又性感的箱子
I never should have opened that diary. It's like Pandora's hot, sexy box.
3P是什么？
What's a threesome?
-什么？ -3P
-What? A threesome.
那是大人们无聊时玩的游戏
That's a game that adults play sometimes when they're bored.
随便啦，  那艾蜜莉怎么样了？
Whatever. So what happened with Emily?
没怎样，  我想等到她来看我
Nothing. I wanted to wait till she came for a visit,
然后我决定做一件很戏剧性的事
and then I decided to do something really dramatic.
那时离初选只剩下一周了
It was just one week before the primary, and I had graduated
我也从培果与卫生纸 升级到布告与汽车帖纸
from bagels and toilet paper to signs and bumper stickers.
(SCREAMS)
老天爷！
Jesus! Mercy!
请稍等
Hold, please.
我在这干什么？
What am I doing here?
过去！再过去一尺！再一尺，  过去！
Move over! Another foot! Go, another foot. Move over!
过去、过去、过去！
Over, over, over!
我只想让大家知道新的布告准备好了
Just want to let everyone know that the new signs are ready.
看来很棒
They're looking good.
我帮史威尼议员写过三次演讲稿
I wrote three speeches for Congressman Sweeney.
(STAPLING CONTINUES)
高中上的怎样？
How's high school?
他是德州人，  名叫乔治布希 但他不是总统
He's from Texas. His name's George Bush. But he is not the President.
他是乔治与芭芭拉的长子
Instead, he's the eldest son of George and Barbara
也是白宫内的参谋之一
and considered a key political advisor of the White House.
布莱特，  你忘了提德州巡逻队
Bryant, well, you forgot to mention the Texas Rangers.
喔，  是的
BRYANT: Oh, okay.
这家伙要是够聪明，  就会回去打棒球
Man, if this guy's smart, he'll go back to baseball.
-真的 -有人看到海约吗？
-No kidding. -Anybody see Hayes?
-没 -没
-No. -No.
海约！海约呢？海约！
Hayes! Where is Hayes? Hayes!
你是你们麦迪逊毕业的高材生 是真的吗？
Is it true you graduated first of your class at Madison?
-嗯 -好吧
-Yeah. -All right.
-过来，  我们去散步 -我们去散步
-Come on. We're walking. -We're walking.
这是目前居住在纽约的麦迪逊校友
Here's a list of Madison graduates in the New York area.
这些人的年收入都超过20万
These people earn 200 grand plus a year.
我们星期一的募款晚宴还剩15席 一万块一人头的位子
We have a $10,000-a-plate fundraiser on Monday with 15 empty tables.
这可不行，  海约 我需要你推销五席出去
I can't have that, Hayes. I need you to sell five of them.
等等，  不用买咖啡与培果了？
Hold on. No more coffee, bagels?
-那得看你这次表现如何，  好吗？ -盖瑞斯
-We'll see how this goes, okay? -Gareth.
-什么？ -谢谢，  我现在很高兴
-What? -Thank you. I'm really happy right now.
-好的，  海约 -好的
-Okay, Hayes. -Okay.
-桌子在那 -你看看，  好
-There's the desk. -Look at that. Yeah.
嗯，很好笑，卫生纸
Yeah, that's funny, the toilet paper.
很讽刺，很棒
That's good because it's ironic.
没错，  大家，  我的桌子
Yeah, that's right, everybody. My desk.
就在这，  我有桌子，  还有名单
Right here, I got a desk, and I got a list.
我还有电话与这个空篮子
And I have a phone. And this empty basket.
不、不、不，  我不认为
No, no, no, I really don't agree
州长的人格有问题，  波尔曼太太
that the Governor has a character problem, Mrs. Perleman.
您知道全美有50%的人认为
Did you know that 50% of Americans believe that
大麻应该合法化吗？
marijuana use should be legalized?
(PHONE LINE DRONES)
喂？
Hello?
不、不、不，  他并未逃避徵兵
No, no, no, he wasn't a draft dodger.
况且，  您知道大多数的美国人都认为
Besides, did you know that the majority of Americans believe
越战是个很糟的点子吗？
that the Vietnam War was just a terrible idea?
两条腿
Both legs.
哗，抱歉，  您一定很想念它们
Wow, I am sorry. You must miss them.
(PHONE LINE DRONES)
是，  我了解你的顾虑 但我想您应该要记得
Yes, I understand your concern, but I think you should remember
州长的家乡是个名为希望的小镇
that the Governor comes from a town called Hope.
他也象征著希望，  所以…
And hope is exactly what he stands for, so...
不、不，  我知道那很土，  但我也认为
No, no, I know it's corny, but I also think
有时这国家所需的正是一点土气
that sometimes corny is exactly what this country needs.
那太好了，  不，  谢谢您
That would be wonderful. No, thank you.
两个位子
Two seats.
好的，  谢谢您，  毕雪先生
Okay, great. Thank you, Mr. Bishop.
是的，  餐会在下星期四
Yeah, the dinner's next Thursday.
是的，  我今早与希拉蕊通过话
Yes, when I spoke with Hillary this morning
她说她想要更深入认识 我们最重要的支持者
she said that she wanted to get to know our most important supporters.
不，  我相信您会很高兴认识她的
No, I think you'd definitely enjoy meeting her.
嗯
Yeah.
一整桌？不，  那绝对有可能
An entire table? No, that is very possible.
我就帮您订下一桌罗，  太好了
I'll put you down for one table, then. That sounds great.
好的，  我很期待下星期四与您会面
Okay, I look forward to seeing you next Thursday.
好的，  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
我刚卖了一整桌5万
I just sold an entire table for $50,000.
(ALL CHEERING)
那是我的人，  威尔，  我的人
That's my guy, Will. My guy.
卫生纸家伙！卫生纸家伙！
ALL: (CHANTING) Toilet paper guy! Toilet paper guy!
先生们，  晚安，  请给我一包摩立红烟
Good evening, gentlemen. Pack of Reds, please.
三块六毛，  多了新税与警示
3.60. New tax and a new warning.
老天
Christ.
警告：  吸烟将导致漫长并痛苦的死亡
说实话吧，  朋友
Tell us the truth, my friend.
-柯林顿到底有没有拉麻？ -有差吗？
-Did that Clinton inhale or not? -What does it matter?
那就像是你女朋友抓到你 与另一个女人在床上，  然后你说
That's like if your girlfriend catches you in bed with another woman, then you say,
“可是我们没做”
"But we didn't do it."
-对她来说有差吗？ -有差啊，  嗨
-What, is that gonna matter to her? -Yeah, it does. Hi.
-哈罗 -请给我一包美鹰蓝烟
-Hello. -Pack of American Eagles, blue, please.
四块两毛五
4.25.
四块两毛五？ 你花四块两毛五买一包烟？
4.25? You pay $4.25 for a pack of cigarettes?
里面的化学物品比较少
They don't put as many chemicals in them.
-所以是健康的香烟罗 -算是吧
-So those are healthy cigarettes. -Something like that.
若没有那么多的化学品
So if there's not as many chemicals in them,
你不觉得应该要比较便宜才对吗？
they should cost less, not more, don't you think?
你的烟里渗有硝酸钾
They put saltpeter in your cigarettes,
让它们烧得比较快，  也让你抽更多
which make them burn faster, which make you smoke more.
意思就是，  你的烟其实比较贵
Which means, at the end of the day, your cigarettes actually cost more, not less.
影印小妹，  我觉得你买的
Copy girl, what I think you're actually paying for
是一个有漂亮粉色系老鹰的图像
is the picture of the eagle and the pretty pastel colors.
一个让你对生活方式放心的说词 其余的都是狗屎
Some reassuring idea about your lifestyle. The rest is pretty much crap.
-要赌吗？ -好啊
-You wanna bet? -Sure.
-20元 -我有20元
-20 bucks. -I got 20 bucks.
最好赚的20元
Easiest 20 bucks I ever made.
-真的？ -嗯
-Really? -Yeah.
很有趣，  等会我就有40元了
That's funny. In a minute, I'll have 40.
好，  我们要同时吸入同样的份量
Okay, we have to inhale at the same time for the same amount of time.
-对 -预备，  开始
-Yep. -Ready, steady, go.
-今天是我生日 -生日快乐
-It's my birthday today. -Happy birthday.
怎么没出去庆祝？
Why aren't you out celebrating?
我男友卢卡斯本来要带我去吃饭 然后去参加派对
My boyfriend, Lucas, was taking me out for dinner and then to a party.
但他临时有工作要去费城 当然，  他接下了这工作是因为…
But at last minute, he gets a gig in Philly, which, of course, he takes 'cause...
老实说，  他对成为下一个
Truth is he's far more interested in being
柯特寇本的兴趣比当我男友要大多了
the next Kurt Cobain than being my boyfriend.
柯特寇本是谁？
Who's Kurt Cobain?
你在开玩笑吧？
You're kidding me!
什么？
What?
抽烟
Smoke.
Oh.
-你看 -你看
-Look at that. -Look at that.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
(GROANS)
(LAUGHING)
-好吧 -不，  别这样
-All right. -No, come on.
光是知道我是对的
The satisfaction of me being right
而你错了的满足感就足够了
and you being wrong is more than enough for me.
我从来不耍赖的，  不如这样吧
Well, I never welsh on a bet, so I'll tell you what.
我请你吃晚餐，  当是生日晚餐
I'll take you out for dinner, for a birthday dinner.
-怎么样？ -像是约会吗？
-What do you say? -Like a date?
不，  我不是这意思
No, I didn't mean it like that.
像是“我可怜你
Like an "I feel sorry for you
“过生日竟然还没计划”的晚餐
"because it's your birthday and you have no plans" dinner.
-那种的 -嗯，  那这样吧
-You know, one of those. -Well, I'll tell you what.
你可以带我去我原本要去的派对
You can take me to this party I have to go to,
因为我可没法单独去面对
because there's no way I can face going alone.
(TRIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
嗯，  我想我该去…
Yeah, I'm gonna go head over...
Whoa.
我感觉很突兀
I think I'm a little out of my league here.
你是啊
Yes, you are.
艾蜜莉是你的大学女友？
So Emily is what, like, your college sweetheart?
-你这种做法真的很厉害 -什么？
-It's amazing how you do that. -What?
你可以将一句很简单的话
The way you take the simplest statement,
扭曲成一个很负面的话
and then you twist it with a completely negative connotation.
-真的很厉害，  我很佩服 -我不是那意思
-It's really, actually, impressive. I'm amazed. -I didn't mean to do that.
-但我懂，  我了 -我其实觉得那很感人
-But I understand. I get it. -I actually think it's very sweet.
-看，  你又来了 -真的？
-See, you did it again. -Really?
-嗯 -我自己都没察觉
-Yeah. -I don't even know I'm doing it.
你或许很难想像 一个基于互相尊重的恋情
It's probably hard for you to imagine a relationship based on mutual respect
而不包括一丝丝你所谓的被虐倾向
without even the slightest hint of whatever you call it, masochism.
你与艾蜜莉的关系 若真像你说的那么完美
Well, if your deal with Emily is so gosh darn wonderful,
你为什么不娶她呢？
then why don't you just marry her?
什么阻止了你？
What's stopping you?
没有啊
Nothing.
-哗 -哗
-Wow. -Wow.
她明天就会收到了，  我订了位
She gets it tomorrow. I made a reservation
在上东区一家很高档的法国餐厅
at some fancy French restaurant on the Upper East Side.
天啊，  你要在一群 不认识的人面前求婚？
Oh, my God. You're doing it in front of a room full of strangers?
-是啊，  有什么不妥吗？ -没有，  这表示你很有自信
-Yeah, I am. What's wrong with that? -No, nothing. I think it shows confidence.
你要说什么？
What are you gonna say?
-我还在想，  不知道 -你应该跟我练习
-I'm still working on it. I don't know. -Oh, you should work on it with me.
你该跟我练习，  我在这方面很厉害 我来演艾蜜莉
You should practice with me. I'm really good at that. I will be Emily.
我是你的大学女友艾蜜莉 你有什么要问我的吗？
I'm Emily, your college sweetheart. Is there something you wanted to ask me?
-艾蜜莉… -等等！你要跪下来
-Emily... -Wait! You've got to get down on your knee.
不，  我才不要跪下来
No, I'm not getting down on my knee.
她会喜欢的，  她会希望你跪下
She'll like it. She'll like seeing you down on your knee.
-我不要跪下 -那真是错大了，  好吧
-I'm not getting down on my knee. -Such a mistake. Okay.
-艾蜜莉 -是的，  威廉
-Emily. -Yes, William.
别惹我笑，  艾蜜莉
Don't make me laugh. Emily,
你愿意
will you,
um,
嫁给我吗？
marry me?
-不 -我的天
-No. -Oh, my God.
什么叫做“你愿意嫁给我吗？”
Well, what do you mean, "Will you, um, marry me?"
我好几个礼拜没见到你了！
I haven't seen you in weeks!
你对我们的婚姻前景 看来一点都不开心与兴奋！
You don't look happy or excited about the prospect of our marriage!
你要我放弃我的自由
You're asking me to give up my freedom,
我无忧无虑的生活
my joie de vivre
为了一个成功与失败率参半的制度？
for an institution that fails as often as it succeeds?
我为什么要嫁给你？ 你又为什么想要娶我呢？
And why should I marry you, anyway? I mean, why do you wanna marry me?
唯一理由就是能满足社会 深植在我们心中的理想中产阶级欲望
Besides some bourgeois desire to fulfill an ideal that society embeds in us
与自小就灌输在我们心中的 消费资本主义
from an early age to promote a consumer capitalist agenda?
Oh!
我的天啊！
(CHUCKLING) Oh, my God!
-你应该要跪下的 -闭嘴啦！
-You should've got on your knee! -Just shut up!
这样
Here.
我想娶你，  是因为你是我一早起来
I wanna marry you because you're the first person
第一眼就想要见到的人
that I want to look at when I wake up in the morning
并是我每晚睡前唯一想要吻的人
and the only one I wanna kiss goodnight.
因为当我第一次看到那双手时
Because the first time that I saw these hands,
我就无法想像不能牵著它们的日子
I couldn’t imagine not being abIe to hold them.
但最主要的，  当你爱一个人 像我爱你一样
But mainly, when you love someone as much as I love you
唯一剩下的就是结婚
getting married is the only thing left to do.
所以你愿意…
So will you...
Um...
嫁给我吗？
marry me?
绝对是，  或许
Definitely. Maybe.
我得考虑一下
I have to think about it.
能送我回家吗？
Walk me home?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
-要不要喝杯茶？ -嗯，  好啊
-Do you want a cup of tea? -Yeah. I'd love one.
嘿
Hey.
你为什么有这么多版本的《简爱》？
How come you have so many copies of Jane Eyre?
-说来话长 -真的？
-It's a long story. -Really?
看上去好像只有三百多页
It seems to be about 300 pages or so.
(LAUGHS)
说真的，  为什么？
Seriously, why?
我13岁生日时，  想要一副金耳环
For my 13th birthday, I wanted a pair of gold stud earrings,
但我爸却帮我买了精装版的《简爱》
and instead my dad bought me a hardcover copy of Jane Eyre.
里头还有他很美的题词 但我当时根本不在乎
And inside, he wrote a beautiful inscription, which I could care less about at the time
因为我还在为了耳环的事生气
seeing as I was so pissed about the earrings,
真的很遗憾 因为那是他给我最后的一份礼物
which was tragic as it turned out 'cause it was the last present he ever gave me.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他在三周后因车祸身亡
He died three weeks later in a car accident.
老天，  太惨了
Jesus. That's awful.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-你看过这本书吗？ -没有
-Have you ever read it? -No.
我每一、两年就读一次 每次都不一样
I read it every year or two. Each time it's different.
每次都得到不同的讯息
It tells me different things.
我去上大学时，  我妈把房子卖了
Anyhow, when I went away to college, my mom sold our house
在这之间，  那本《简爱》弄丢了
and somewhere along the way, Jane Eyre got lost.
现在我只要一经过二手书店
Now, every time I pass a second-hand bookstore,
就会找我爸买给我的那本
I look for the copy that my dad bought me for my birthday.
(COME AS YOU ARE PLAYING)
我知道我找不到了
I know I'll never find it.
很蠢，  但这变成了一个怪又迷信的…
It's stupid, but it's become this, like, weird superstitious little...
-不会蠢啦 -多谢，  兴趣
-It's not stupid. -Thanks. Hobby.
这些是什么？
What are all these?
这些是我找到里面有题词的
Oh, these are the ones I found that have inscriptions.
“愿能有再次爱与希望与梦想的机会 爱莉丝留”
"With love and hopes and dreams of second chances. Alice."
这是什么？
What is this?
这是柯特寇本，  这是超脱乐团 你喜欢吗？
This is Kurt Cobain. This is Nirvana. Do you like it?
我喜欢
Yeah, I do.
你觉得我想要当 政治家很无稽，  对吗？
You think it's ridiculous that I want to be a politician, don't you?
-对 -谢谢你
-Yes. -Thank you.
不、不，  我了解想从政的理想 对你有好感并不难
No, no, I get the whole politician thing. It's easy to like you.
那倒是真的，  的确
That's true. That's very true.
我很怀疑你是否希望 人家喜欢你过了头
I just wonder if you want people to like you a little too much.
那倒也是
That's also true.
我应该要他们讨厌我
I should want them to hate me.
我马上就开始朝那方向前进 你有什么忠告吗？
I'm gonna start working on that right away. You got any tips for me?
不，  你已有个好的开始
No, but you're off to a great start.
-是吗？ -我已经开始讨厌你了
-Yeah? -I'm hating you already.
很好
Good.
你长大后想要做什么？
What do you wanna be when you grow up?
我是说影印与带小孩对你来说
I mean, you're too smart to be making Xeroxes
-太浪费了 -不
-and babysitting. -No.
-我不知道！ -还有一些有的没的
-I don't know! -Whatever else you do.
我不知道，  我也不知道 要怎样才能知道，  你知道吗？
I don't know, and I don't know how to know. You know?
(SIGHS)
我真的想做的是
You know what I really wanna do
我想去些我完全不了解的地方
is I wanna go to all those places that I know nothing about.
我一直在存钱
I've been saving money.
但我连这件事都搞不定
But I can't even get it together to do that.
或许是因为我走进了这家伙的死胡同
Probably because I'm stuck in a rut with this guy.
你该甩了他
You should dump him.
我知道这不关我的事，  但他配不上你
I know that's none of my business, but you're too good for him.
真的
You are.
-你知道酷的是什么吗？ -不知道
-You know what's really cool? -I don't.
我们俩可以就坐在这里，  不用去担心
We can just sit here and we don't have to worry about
-调情与吸引力之类的 -那些有的没的
-flirting or all the attraction stuff. All that stuff.
非常酷
Very cool.
嗯
Yeah.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
我得走了
I got to go.
白痴！
Dumbass!
《纽约客杂志》
-天啊 -他回来了！
-Oh, God. - There he is!
-就跟你说不会很久 -嗨！我想给你个惊喜！
-Told you he wouldn’t be long. -Hi! I wanted to surprise you!
-我搭隔夜的班机来的！ -太棒了！
-I took the red-eye! -(WHEEZING) That's incredible!
我才在跟艾蜜莉说亚瑟 派你与先锋队伍去阿尔巴尼
I was just telling Emily how Arthur sent you to Albany as part of the advance team.
-先锋队伍 -对啊，  怎么样？
Advance team. - Yeah. How'd it go?
-怎么样？老兄，顺利极了！ -很好
-How'd it go? Man, it went great! -Great.
-很好 -很好
-Great. -Great.
-你没事吧？ -没事，  我只是运动一下
-Are you okay? -Oh, yeah, I was just getting a little exercise.
-我跑上楼梯 -喔
-I ran up the stairs. -Okay.
我要去办公室，  这…明天会很忙 很高兴认识你
I'm going to the office. It's... Got a big day. Nice meeting you.
-你也是 -好
-And you. -Okay.
好
Okay.
祝你好运
(WHISPERING) Good luck.
-嗨 -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
-这里 -嗯
-Here. -Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
-很怪，  你的舌头味道不一样 -什么？
-It's weird. Your tongue tastes different. -What?
你的舌头味道不一样
It tastes different, your tongue.
-真奇怪 -不坏，  就是不一样
-That is weird. -It's not bad. It's just different.
或许是这里的自来水吧
Maybe it's the tap water here.
再不然就是酸碱平衡… 我不知道自己在胡言乱语些什么
Or the pH balance... I don't know what I'm talking about.
就跟你说纽约会改变你
Told you New York was gonna change you.
-我们可以去散个步吗？ -嗯
-Could we maybe go for a walk? -Yeah.
-去透透气好吗？ -嗯，  你可以参观一下纽约
-Just to get some air? -Yeah, you could see New York.
好啊
I would love that.
-我有跟你说… -我本来…
So, did I ever tell you...  I was gonna...
-抱歉，  不，  你说 -什么？
-Oh, sorry. No, go. -What?
我刚才在说，  我有跟你说过 我爸跟我妈求婚那天的事吗？
I was gonna say, did I ever tell you about the day my dad proposed to my mom?
没有
No.
爸正在要去跟我妈求婚的路上
Well, Dad was on his way to meet my mom to propose,
撞见了他的前女友卡罗琳哈普
and he runs into his ex-girlfriend, Caroline Hopper.
他们交谈著，  看著对方
And they're talking, they're looking at each other,
那些旧感情突然又浮现
and all these old feelings, they start coming up.
他开始想
And he's thinking,
(SIGHS)
“我现在可以与卡罗琳哈普私奔
"I could run away right now with Caroline Hopper,
“做个快乐的人
"be a happy man.
“我只需要吻她”
"All I have to do is kiss her."
但是他却抬起头
But instead, he looks up,
看到我妈从转角走过来
and he sees my mom walking around the corner.
那刹那他明白了自己没什么好惧怕的
And that moment he knows that he had no reason to be afraid.
你懂吗？
You understand?
我在这故事中是卡罗琳哈普 还是你妈？
Am I Caroline Hopper in this story or your mom?
(EMILY GASPS)
天啊！我是你妈！
Oh, my God! I'm your mom!
-艾蜜莉，  今早看见你时… -威尔，  拜托
-Emily, when I saw you this morning... -Will, please.
-…我知道… -把那放回你的口袋里
-... I knew... -Put that back in your pocket.
-站起来，  威尔，  停止 -…一切都很清晰
-Just stand up, Will. Stop. -...with absolute clarity.
-等等 -我没有理由惧怕
-Wait, wait, wait. -I have no reason to be afraid.
-我们谈谈 -我不害怕
-Let's think about this. -I'm not afraid of this.
就像是那天我…
It's just like the day that my...
威尔！
Will!
我跟查理上了床！
I slept with Charlie!
(BIRDS FLUTTERING)
(SIGHS)
我以为我们有计划
I thought we had a plan.
威尔，  是你有计划，  威尔 你有很大的计划！
Well, you had a plan, Will. You have a really big plan!
-我满确定是我俩的计划 -我无法继续假装
-Pretty sure we both had that plan. -I just can't keep pretending
-自己想成为计划的一部份 -计划的时候
-that I want to be part of it anymore. -You were there
-你也在场 -我不知道如何跟你说
-when we made it. -And I didn't know how to tell you.
该如何去跟你在乎的人
How do you tell someone that you care about
说你要的与他们要的
that you don't want the same things
-已经不同 -最好的方式吗？
-they want anymore? -The best way?
绝对是与他的室友上床
Definitely having sex with the roommate.
(SIGHS)
很没种，  我很抱歉
It was cowardly, and I'm sorry.
真好
Oh, good.
(GROANING)
你让我好痛苦
You're killing me.
不，  我没有，  我放你走
No, I'm not. I'm letting you go.
因为我们若继续在一起，  威尔 会让彼此都痛苦
'Cause if we stay together, Will, we're gonna be miserable.
我会妨碍你追求你那些…
I'm gonna hold you back from all these...
-才不是这样 -…伟大的梦想
-That's not true. -...incredible dreams that you have.
最后你会因此而恨我
And then, eventually, you're totally gonna hate me for it.
不 -会
-No. -Yes.
威尔，  你我都不希望这样
Will, I don't want that, and you don't want that.
相信我
Trust me.
你会没事的，  海约先生
You're gonna be just fine, Mr. Hayes,
就算没有我
without me.
哗
Wow.
是啊
Yeah.
哗
Wow.
汤姆布洛考在纽约报导
ANNOUNCER: Here is Tom Brokaw in New York.
晚安，  比尔柯林顿或许在纽约受伤
Good evening. Bill Clinton may have been wounded in New York,
但问题是，伤害有多深呢？
but the big question tonight is, to what degree?
毕竟他存活了
Because, after all, he is the big survivor, indeed, the victor
轻易的赢得了纽约初选
in the New York primary and by a comfortable margin.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
预计胜者-纽约州与堪萨斯州 柯林顿
(TOM CHATTERING ON TV)
围绕月亮
WOMEN: (SINGING) Goes 'round the moon
我看见你眼中的热情
I see the passion in your eyes
有时却完全是惊喜
Sometimes it's all a big surprise
因为我曾经
'Cause there was a time when all I did
(ALL CHATTERING)
嘿
Hey.
恭喜
Congratulations.
我听说他们要求你留下 你一定很开心吧
I hear they asked you to stay on. You must be very happy.
嗯，  他的确，  我是，  非常、非常快乐
Yeah, yeah, he did, and I am. Very, very happy.
真的？为何我觉得 我应该将刀片都藏起来？
Really? Why do I feel like I should hide the razor blades?
还有钉书机与那些剪刀？
And the staplers and those scissors?
我会没事的 但这首歌真是让人想死啊
I'll be fine. But this song, it's an excellent cure for the will to live.
我知道，  那跳舞的那些呢？ 让他们停止吧
I know. What about the dancing? Make that end.
(CHUCKLES)
那晚很抱歉
I'm sorry about the other night.
没关系，  我只是想卢卡斯 应该不会很高兴
It's okay. I just didn't think that Lucas would approve.
-艾蜜莉应该也是 -嗯
-Or Emily, for that matter. -(SCOFFS) Well.
况且，  我们在一起一定会像猫与狗
Besides, you and me, it'd kind of be like cats and dogs.
对、对
Yeah. Yeah.
-油与水 -沙纸与光屁屁
-Oil and water. -Sandpaper and bare ass.
-好恶心，  有够恶心 -屁屁是你
-That's gross. That's just gross. -You'd be the ass.
嗯，  不，  多谢了
Yeah. No, thank you.
-我太荣幸了 -蓝侬与麦卡尼
-I'd be honored. -Lennon and McCartney.
-他俩很合 -只有一阵子
-They were good together. -Yeah, while it lasted,
然后就连朋友都做不成
and then they couldn’t even be friends.
(LAUGHING)
-我想那方面我们应该没问题 -我也是这么想
-I think we can, at least, manage that. -I think we could.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
-幸会 -干杯
-Enchanté. -Yeah. Salud.
-走嘛，  我们去跳舞 -不要
-Come on, let's dance. -No.
-为什么？ -好啦
-Why? -Okay.
-准备好了吗？ -嗯
You ready?  Yeah.
艾蜜莉就这样了吧
Guess that's it for Emily.
女朋友们-特质
我真不敢相信她与查理练习
I can't believe that she rehearsed with Charlie.
-我也不敢相信 -那就剩艾波，  或许是夏曼
-I can't believe it, either. -That leaves April. Maybe Summer.
-还有人吗？ -我太忙了
-Anybody else? -I was too busy.
为了竞选忙得要死
I was too busy working on the campaign.
反正，  柯林顿当选后
Anyway, when Clinton got elected,
罗素与我成立了一家顾问公司
Russell and I started our own consulting firm,
(CAMERA CLICKING)
我们帮大家竞选
and we worked on campaigns for everybody.
市议员、州议员
City council, state senate.
甚至附近抓狗的
We even did one for the local dog catcher.
很有趣，  爸，  但那些女友呢？
That's very interesting, Dad, but what about girlfriends?
-妈呢？ -我又开始约会
-What about Mom? -Well, I started dating again.
-但不是很认真 -艾波呢？她怎么样了？
-But nothing serious. -What about April? What happened to her?
嗯，  柯特寇本死了一周后 她与男友分手了
Well, a week after Kurt Cobain died, she broke up with her boyfriend.
她跑去旅行
She went traveling.
环游世界，  实现了她的梦想
She traveled all over the world, just like she always dreamed of doing.
她说是因为
And she says that it was because of something
我在她生日时跟她说过的话
that I said to her on her birthday.
我们先互写名信片，  然后开始通信
Anyway, we started writing postcards. We started writing letters.
不知不觉中，  虽然我们相隔万里
And before I knew it, even though we were separated by entire worlds,
我们成了好朋友
we became great friends.
《简爱》
1994年，  纽约充满生气
It was 1994, and New York was full of new life.
更多的工作与财富
More jobs, more money.
敬请期待网路！
That was the start of the Internet. And overnight, everyone in Manhattan
那是网路的开始 在一夜之间，  所有曼哈顿的人
都拿著手机
had a cell phone.
听得到我吗？
Can you hear me now?
并机不离手
Which they never put down.
然后我们的旧上司亚瑟罗布雷多 给了罗素和我千载难逢的机会
And then, our old boss, Arthur Robredo gave Russell and me our first big break.
-这是给你的 -谢谢
-This just came for you. -Thanks.
我终于跨进了那扇门
I had finally made it inside the room.
-盖瑞斯 -海约
-Gareth. -Hayes.
早安
Good morning.
嘿，  上工罗
Hey, let's get this party started.
北部那边怎样？
What's the word from upstate?
生平第一次，  纽约的大头主动来找我
For the first time, New York was coming to me,
而不是我去求他们
instead of the other way around.
一切下滑
“我国最濒临绝种的
"The most endangered species in our nation
“不是大啄木鸟或是什么淡水鱼
"isn't a big woodpecker or some freshwater fish.
“而是我们脑中的语言！
"It's the tongue in our heads!
“听听当今这些不成伦的语言
"Listen to the truncated bastard language of today.
“平均词汇只剩一百年前的三分之一
"The average vocabulary is a third of what it was 100 years ago.
“话才说出口就死于脚前！
"Words fall out of our mouths and die at our feet!
“词汇的远景被屠宰
"The landscape of vocabulary is being hacked down
“被流行文化扭曲得不伦不类
"and grubbed up by the dribble of pop culture,
“惨遭懒散的淫秽玷污…”
"poisoned by lazy obscenity..."
威尔？
(WHISPERING) Will?
“…被崇拜年轻的媒体婴儿化…”
HAMPTON: "...infantilized by a youth-obsessed media..."
-嘿 -嘿
-Hey. -Hey.
是我最喜欢的小毛头 你看来成熟多了
It's my favorite man-boy. You look very manly.
谢谢、谢谢，  我是这么打算的啦
Well, thank you, thank you. That's the aim.
-艾蜜莉如何？ -艾蜜莉
-How's Emily? -Emily.
她现在是别人日记里的女主角了
She's starring in somebody else’s diary now.
Oh.
-教授如何？ -教授很好
-How's the Professor? -The Professor is wonderful.
-他很搞笑 -为了个大二生甩了我
-He's funny. -He dumped me for a sophomore.
跟我说是为我好
Told me it was for my own good.
最近好像很流行这句
Everybody seems to be using that line these days.
你最近都在干嘛？
What have you been up to?
帮《纽约杂志》写些很蠢的东西
I'm writing these really dumb items for New York Magazine.
等著熬出头
Waiting for my big break.
“而“语法”不是内华达州的妓院 付给国税局的税
"And 'syntax' isn't what Nevada brothels pay the IRS."
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
-我去听教授演讲 -好啊
-I'm gonna go listen to the Professor. -Sure.
眼镜很好看
Nice glasses.
“有机会去听听你们的孩子说话”
HAMPTON: "Listen to your kids if you can."
-谢谢 -麻烦威士忌加冰
Thank you.  Scotch, rocks, please.
威廉海约！
William Hayes!
是从…别告诉我！
From... Don't tell me!
威斯康辛州来的！对，  乳酪产地
Wisconsin! Yes, the Cheese State.
很高兴你能参加我们这小聚会
Very nice of you to come to our little shindig.
-麻烦再来一杯 -我的荣幸
-I'll have another, please. -PIeasure.
嗯，  夏曼跟我说 你在帮亚瑟罗布雷多写讲稿？
Yeah. Summer tells me you're writing speeches now for Arthur Robredo?
-她跟我说你的新女友是大二生 -不，  其实是两个大一生
-She tells me you're dating a sophomore. -No. Actually, it's two freshmen,
情况好时可凑成一个大二生吧
which, on a good day, add up to a sophomore, I suppose.
陪我走走，  你怎么会为 亚瑟罗布雷多这种政客卖力？
WaIk with me. Why would you wanna work for a hack like Arthur Robredo?
我记得我们初次会面时 你是个有原则与抱负的人
As I recall from our first encounter, you're a man of principles and ideals, even.
别跟我说你也只是另一个 穿著亚曼尼西装的雅痞
Don't tell me you're just another yuppie puppy in an Armani suit.
你讲得好好，  亲爱的 他还有礼吗？你对他有礼吗？
You were wonderful, darling. Is he being nice? You being nice?
-有礼？他顶得住的 -当然，  我顶得住
-Nice? Yeah, he can handle himself. -Sure, I can handle myself.
首先，  亚瑟罗布雷多不是政客 他是从基层做起的
First of all, Arthur Robredo is not a hack. He's worked his way up from the streets.
他曾是警察、实业家
He was a cop, an entrepreneur.
他是个白痴，  我的书的主题就是这个
He's a putz. This is exactly what my book is about.
拿去，  读读吧，  免费的
Here. Read it. It's free.
美丽、理想、爱都一文不值
Beauty, ideals, love don't mean squat anymore.
-重要的只是权力与金钱 -你的每本书我都拜读过
-It's all about power and money. -I've read every single one of your books,
而你才完全为权力与金钱著迷
and you're completely obsessed with power and money.
那是因为他两者都没有 是吧，  宝贝？
That's because he doesn't have any. Right, babe?
宝贝，  我最在乎的是爱
Babe, I am about the love.
-你知道的 -对
-As you know. -Yes.
所以你才留我在身边
That's why you keep me around.
好管住你那又野又贪婪的野心
To keep that rampant, rapacious ambition of yours in check.
我有个想法
I have a thought.
你不如利用你那一丁点的 权力与影响力
Why don't you use that newly acquired scintilla of power and influence
让夏曼帮你那罗布雷多的家伙 写篇文章？
to get Summer here to write an article about your man Robredo?
这样一来，  能让夏曼出头 你也能散播你的信息
That way Summer gets a break, and you get the word out.
-你得到了什么呢，  汉普顿？ -是啊
-What do you get, Hampton? -Yeah.
我想是爱吧，  更多的爱 我就只在乎这个
I guess it's the love. More of the love. Yeah, that's what I'm about.
更多爱
More love.
-我就知道夏曼会再出现 -是吗？
- I knew Summer would be back. -Did you?
你知道吗？我一开始 并不希望夏曼是我母亲
You know what? At first, I didn't want Summer to be my mom.
但我现在还满喜欢她的 你有约她出去吗？
But now I'm kinda liking her. Did you ask her out on a date?
Uh-uh.
我很想，  但我不能 因为文章出自她笔
I wanted to, but I couldn’t 'cause she was writing the article.
罗布雷多为何无法谨言慎行 纽约打击犯罪铁腕的民主党员
-哗，  写得真不错 -威尔，  这篇很棒
-Wow. This is pretty good. -Will, this is really good.
(DIALING)
你确定不会像拍马屁的文章？
SUMMER: Are you sure it didn't seem like a puff piece?
不会，很完美，  完全…
No, it's perfect. It's absolutely...
不过有一部份让我有点困扰
You know, there's one part, though, that kind of bothered me.
“威廉海约
"William Hayes,
罗布雷多主要的讲稿作者 不仅热枕并带有纯真的帅气
"Robredo's chief speech writer, is both intense and boyishly handsome."
-纯真？我是说… -对
-Boyishly? I mean... -Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
我本来是写
You know, I originally wrote,
“威廉海约有著一双勾人的双眼 与吸引人的长相
"William Hayes has seductive eyes and the intriguing looks of someone
“让人想剥光他的衣服”
"whose clothes you wanna rip from his very body,"
但是编辑逼我改掉
but the editor made me change it.
新闻界已经没有让事实存活的空间了
There's just no room for truth in journalism.
你一直都想要成为记者吗？
Did you always want to be a journalist?
不，  16岁之前我一直想当演员 我想在百老汇唱歌
No. Until I was 16, I wanted to be an actress. I wanted to sing on Broadway.
哗，  真的？
Wow. Really?
是啊，  真的，很难以置信吗？
Yeah, really. Is that hard to believe?
嗯，  女演员不都极度需要关注 很情绪化并没有安全感吗？
Well, aren't actresses needy and emotional and, you know, insecure?
都那个样
That sort of thing.
你想说什么？我不需要关注？ 我没有情绪吗？
What are you saying? That I don't need? That I don't have emotions?
-我是个非常需要关注的人 -我不是这意思
-I'm an incredibly needy person. -I'm not saying that.
-我很需要关注 -你懂我想说什么吗？
-I'm a very needy person. -You know what I'm saying?
我是说我想听一首歌
I'm saying I would love to hear a song.
-抱歉？ -来首歌吧
-I'm sorry? -Give us a song.
-你要我为你唱歌 -有何不可？
-You want me to sing you a song? -Why not?
-你有最喜欢的歌吗？ -有
-You have a favorite? -Yes.
-有喔？ -是啊
-You do? -Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
(CLEARING THROAT)
世上成千上万的
(SINGING) How glad the many millions
提摩西与威廉将多么快乐
Of Timothys and Williams would be
-我也是威廉之一 -别打岔
-I'm a William. -Don't interrupt.
若他们捕获我
To capture me
但你如此的执著
But you had such persistence
磨去了我的防备
You wore down my resistance
我坠入了
I fell
感觉真好
And it was swell
不是因为你俊俏
It's not that you're attractive
哗
Wow.
能求你换上它吗？
Will you please put it on?
真的不会不好看
You know, it really isn't so bad.
但你知道有趣的是什么吗？ 它要一千元
You know what the funny part is? It's $1,000.
我迷恋著你，  甜心
I've got a crush on you, sweetie pie
法兰克辛纳屈、琳达朗丝黛
Frank Sinatra, Linda Ronstadt.
-为什么？ -一大堆
-Why? A whole bunch of these.
若你看看后面 它们都有一个共同的歌，  就是…
Well, if you look on the back, they all have one common song, which is...
-  《我迷恋著你》 -每一张都有
-I've Got A Crush On You. -Every one of them.
-进度如何？ -还有很多要做
-How's it going? -Still got a lot to do.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
-嗯，  我差不多了 -嗯，  我也是
-Yeah, I'm about done. -Yeah, me, too.
这世界会原谅我的热情
The world will pardon my mush
因为我迷恋著，  我的宝贝
'Cause I've got a crush, my baby, on...
我打鼾吗？
Was I snoring?
Uh-uh.
你知道我没试过什么吗？
You know what I've never done?
什么？
What?
我从没跟个好男人赖在床上一整天过
I've never spent the whole day in bed with a really great guy.
我也是
Me, neither.
我说真的
I'm serious.
我总是想著有更重要的事要做
I always think of something more important to do.
我是个工作狂
(WHISPERS) I'm a workaholic.
(WILLIAM EXCLAIMS)
很糟糕
It's really bad.
你愿意跟我在床上赖一天吗？
Will you spend the whole day in bed with me?
我们什么都不做
We do nothing.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS)
嗨，  这是夏曼，  请留言，  我会回电
Hi, this is Summer. Please leave a message, and I will call you back.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
我是莱文史坦医师
This is Dr. Levenstein
这是哥伦比亚 基督长老教会医院的急诊室，  我们…
from the Columbia Presbyterian emergency room. We have...
急诊室？喂？
Emergency room? Hello?
-罗斯先生的大动脉破裂 -那究竟是什么意思？
-Mr. Roth has had an aortal rupture. -What does that mean exactly?
就像是在高速公路上
Think of it like a tire blowing out on the highway
开得太快、太久后突然爆胎
after going too fast for way too long.
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
怎么样，  罗斯先生？还可以吗？
How's that, Mr. Roth? Are you comfortable?
我赚得还够
I make a living.
(BOTH SNIGGERING)
拜托，  甜心，  笑一个嘛 我一辈子都在等著讲这个笑话
Come on, sweetheart, give me a smile. I've waited my whole life to do that joke.
可怜的汉普顿
Poor Hampton.
Ow!
夏曼来了
Summer's come.
-他来干嘛？ -你好，  汉普顿
-What's he doing here? -Hello, Hampton.
你好
Hello.
(CHATTERING ON PHONE)
(SUMMER LAUGHING)
就只剩这个没挨他们的刀
One thing they've left intact.
不、不、不，  别提到草根政治运动
No, no, no, no, no, no, don't mention grassroots.
别提到同化
Don't mention osmosis.
你跟那小鬼在一起让我很困扰
It's killing me that you're going out with the kid.
真的？不是烟酒与大二生？
Really? It's not the booze or the cigarettes or the sophomores?
-跟那一点关系都没有 -一点关系都没有
-That has nothing to do with this. -Nothing to do with it.
听著，  我要你知道 我将器官都捐赠给医疗研究
Listen, I want you to know I've donated my organs to medical science
除了一个，  是留给你的
except for one, which is for you.
-甜心，  你真好 -不，  不是那个
-Sweetie, that's so kind. -No, no, not that.
是我的心，  傻瓜
My heart, stupid.
(LAUGHING)
请告诉我你没有爱上他
Please tell me you're not in love with him.
我不能
I can't do that.
(SIGHS)
能给我支烟吗？临死前最后的愿望
Can I have a cigarette? Just a dying man's last request.
别想了，  天啊，  你真的很歇斯底里
Not happening. God, you're such a drama queen.
没人要死了
Nobody's dying.
你又怎会在乎我爱不爱他呢？
What do you care if I'm in love with him, huh?
是你介绍我们认识的，  记得吗？
You're the one who set us up, remember?
是啊，  但我本以为你会玩玩他就算了
Yeah, well, I kind of figured you'd chew him up and spit him out.
你真是个好人，  你好帖心喔 你知道吗？
You're such a sweetie. You're a sweet guy, you know that?
-我读了罗布雷多的那篇 -是喔
-I read the Robredo piece. -Yeah.
那家伙从政了20多年
The guy's been in New York politics for over 20 years
你却只挖得出他女儿是饮食疾患？
and all you can dig up is that his daughter had an eating disorder?
你想说什么，  汉普顿？
What are you saying, Hampton?
做好你的工作
Do your job.
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
每日新闻 柯林顿支持罗布雷多
I can't believe we're finally gonna meet the President.
我真不敢相信我们终于要会见总统
-你看看 -你看看
-Look at that. -Look at it.
我们可不是当年 在第8街小旅馆那两个人了
We've come a long way from that hotel room on 8th Avenue.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我不敢相信！我不敢相信！
GARETH: I don't believe it! I don't believe it!
哪个白痴忘了检查菜单和程序表？
Which idiot forgot to check the menus and the programmes?
菜单与程序表上都没有工会的徽章
There's no union seal on the menus or the programmes.
真的假的？
Are you serious?
饭店员工不让任何人进来
The hotel workers won't let anybody into the building.
卡车司机工会的人不肯架卫星传讯！
The Teamsters won't set up the satellite feed!
有人看到罗伯特克莱吗？
Has anyone seen Robert Klein?
我一小时前才看到他 现在人就不见了
I was with him like an hour ago. Now he's gone.
他好像喝挂了
I think he was completely plastered.
我们怎么会知道罗伯特克莱在哪？
How are we supposed to know where Robert Klein is?
你不会相信的，  但芝加哥雹暴
You're not gonna believe this, but there's a hailstorm in Chicago.
谁管芝加哥啊？
Who cares about Chicago?
我们啊，  总统要从芝加哥来
We do. The President's coming in from Chicago.
-好、好 -我们现在没办法管这个
-Okay, okay. -We can't worry about that right now.
我问你，  你怎会让这种事发生？
Let me ask you a question. How could you let this happen?
-什么？你在说什么？ -你为什么冲著她？
-What? What are you talking about? -Why are you jumping down her throat?
等等、等等！ 大家、大家、大家！
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Guys, guys, guys, guys, hey!
嘿，  深呼吸好吗？我们去问饭店
Hey, deep breath, okay? Look, let's just ask the hotel,
看能不能用他们的网路并找个印表机
see if we can use the Internet connection and find a printer.
-我去打给克莱的经理人 -很好
-I'll call Klein’s agent. -Great.
盖瑞斯，  来喝一杯
Gareth, have a drink.
你，  我不知道你是谁 但你的拉链没拉
You, I don't know who you are, but your fly’s down.
你若能穿内裤的话就太好了 我去查芝加哥的天气
Be great if you wore underwear. I'm gonna go check the weather in Chicago.
第7桌可以上菜了 6份意大利面、两份鱼，  快送上去！
Table seven's up. Six pasta. Two fish. Get it out the door, now!
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
(STATIC BUZZING)
他或许不是你们工会的
He may not be in your union,
但他仍是美国总统
but he still happens to be the President of the United States.
记得他吗？若我是你
Remember him? So if I was you,
-我就会叫你的人下车并进来… -盖瑞斯！
-I'd get your men off that truck and in this... -Gareth!
你不能这样跟卡车工会的人说话！ 拜托
You can't talk to a Teamster like that! Come on.
-这家伙… -没事的
-This guy... -Everything's gonna be fine.
你看看
Look, look, check it out.
我下载了工会的徽章
I downloaded a copy of the union seal.
麻烦你帖在菜单上
If you could just please paste it onto a menu,
去影印五百份，  找家有工会的店 我们就安了
make 500 copies, use a union shop. We're gonna be home free, here.
影印？你要我去影印？
Copies? You want me to make copies?
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
每人都有某时期要去影印 现在轮到你了
Well, at some point, we all make copies. Your time is now.
不好笑，  海约，  那很…
That's not funny, Hayes. That's very...
嗯，  真成熟，  你要去哪？
Yeah, that's real mature. Where are you going?
我去散步！半小时后回来
I'm walking! Back in half an hour.
王八蛋
What a dick.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-喂 -威廉海约？
-Yeah. - (WHISPERING) William Hayes?
我就是
Speaking.
我现在正盯著你
I'm watching you right now.
我很清楚你与你朋友罗布雷多的事
And I know all about you and your friend Robredo.
我甚至可以毁了你们两人
In fact, I know so much, I could bring you both down.
真的？
Really?
-请问你是？ -不如我们见个面，  你就知道了？
-Who am I speaking with? -Why don't we meet, and you'll find out?
-你在哪？ -离你很近
-Where are you? -I'm close by.
我对这没什么经验
I don't have a lot of experience with whatever this is.
你越来越接近
You're getting warm.
很近
You're hot.
你好正！
You are so hot!
(APRIL LAUGHING)
骗到你了！
I got you!
我以为你整个夏天都不在
I thought you were gone through the summer.
不，  我原本也这样想 但是发生了件很疯狂的事
No, I thought so, too, but this crazy thing happened.
我在克里特岛美丽的沙漠露营
I mean, I was camping on this beautiful beach in Crete
跟一群很酷的人们 其中有个我喜欢的男的叫派克
with all these really cool people, and there was this guy that I liked, Paco,
深沉又性感，  话很少，  完全是我的型
brooding and sexy, monosyllabic and totally my type.
有天晚上我与派克跳舞时，  他吻了我
One night I'm dancing with Paco and he kisses me,
-很深很棒的一个吻 -请别跟我说细节
-an incredible, deep kiss. - Spare me the details.
-你知道我怎么样吗？ -不知道，  你怎样？
And what do I do? -I don't know. What'd you do?
我开始哭
I start crying.
-眼泪就一直流下脸颊… -你当然会哭
-I mean, tears are rolling down my cheeks... -Of course you start crying.
…结果他没发觉 因为他的手忙著在我身上游走
...which he doesn't notice 'cause, of course, his hands are all over my body,
感觉很好，  但却让我更难过
which felt nice, which made me feel even more upset,
突然间
'cause in a flash
我眼前晃过了 我们现在到未来间的恋情
I saw our entire relationship, from present to future tense.
很火热的开始，  派克享受著我的爱…
I mean, the incredibly hot start, with Paco basking in my love and admiration...
-我们来这干嘛？ -我需要拿个东西
-What are we doing here? -I just got to pick something up.
一下就好
Just take a second.
然后不可避免的一刻 我也不知道为什么…
And then the inevitable moment, and I don't know why it...
-哈罗 -嗨
-Hello. -Hi.
我也不知道为什么会这样 但是每次都这样
I don't know why it happens, but it always does,
那些爱将开始令他厌烦
when all that love and admiration would start to irritate him
然后他就会伤害我
and he'd find some way to hurt me.
他事后当然感到很抱歉
I mean, sure, after, he'd be sorry.
所以…
So...
我决定脱离他美丽的唇
I decided to unlock his beautiful lips from mine,
将他摆在我屁股上的手移开
remove his hand from my ass,
(LAUGHS)
-然后走开 -干得好
-and I walked away. -Good move.
-我离开了，  威尔！离开派克！ -干得好
-I walked away, Will! From Paco! -Good move.
-没有人能抗拒派克！ -我喜欢这故事
-No one walks away from Paco! -I like the story.
感觉像是扭转了命运
And it felt life-changing.
我发觉我得跟个人分享
And I realized I had to tell someone.
当我意识到这个人是谁时
When I realized who that person was,
-好出乎意料 -在这里，  先生
-it was so unexpected. - Here we are, sir.
像是有什么直视著你
It's like when something is staring you in the face
但你却盲目得看不见
and it's like you're too blind to see it.
那是什么？
What's that?
我也有事要对你说
I have some news for you, too.
等等、等等，  你为什么这么生气？
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Why are you so upset?
你不觉得在我们通了这么久的信后
Don't you think it's a little weird we've been writing each other for however long
你竟然没跟我透露
and somehow you neglect to tell me that,
一、你恋爱了，  二、你居然恋爱了
A, you've fallen in love, and, B, you've fallen in love!
-我跟你说过我在约会 -约会
-I told you I was dating someone. -Dating someone.
你才刚帮人家买了订婚戒指！
You just bought a diamond engagement ring for someone!
抱歉，  我对于要跟你说感到紧张
I'm sorry. I think I was just nervous to tell you.
为什么跟我说会让你紧张？
Why would you be nervous to tell me?
不知道
I don't know.
我好爱这女孩
I love this girl so much.
我很希望你能为我高兴
I'd just really like you to be happy for me.
我可以为你高兴 我当然可以为你高兴
I can be happy for you. Of course I can be happy for you.
可怜的艾波
Poor April.
她就像是故事里永远是朋友的那角色
She's like the character in the story who's always been the friend.
然后发现她不想只做朋友
Then she realized she doesn't just want to be the friend.
她其实想当女朋友，  但是太迟了
She wants to be the girlfriend, except it's too late.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你没在听吗？她为了你回来
Weren't you listening? She came home for you.
所有的菜单上都有徽章，老友
GARETH: There's union seals on all the menus, my friend.
芝加哥的天气放晴了，  总统8点会到
The weather cleared in Chicago. The President will be here by 8:00.
小罗呢？
Where's Russ?
他会在餐厅与你和亚瑟碰面
Gonna meet you and Arthur in the restaurant.
我在这比较好笑
ROBERT KLEIN: I'm funnier over here.
(HARMONICA PLAYING)
我腿停不住
I can't stop my leg
你早到了
You're early.
(MOANING)
见到你真好
Good to see you.
-你看来很好 -谢谢，  你也是
-You look great. -Thank you. You, too.
-领带很漂亮 -你最清楚了
-That's a nice tie. -Well, you'd know.
杂志社要我继续跟罗布雷多的报导
So, the magazine asked me to do a follow-up on Robredo.
-很好 -嗯，  是很好，  但也…
-Great. -Yeah, it is great. It's also...
也…
(SIGHING) It's...
你自己看吧
You just read it.
-你已经写好了 -嗯
-You already wrote it. -Yeah.
-他做了这事？ -是的
-He did this? -Yes.
他们让一个朋友提早假释
They actually got a friend an early parole.
你知道吗？这是好久以前的事了
You know what? I think it happened such a long time ago,
你们的问卷调查又领先这么多
and you're way ahead in all the polls.
嗯，  这对他标榜是铁腕打击犯罪的 民主党员不会有什么大影响
Yeah, see, I don't think that's gonna matter, because he's the tough-on-crime Democrat.
那…
That's...
当人们读了这个…
When people read this...
夏曼，  听我说
Summer, listen to me.
你若交了上去，  我们就完了
If you hand this in, we won't survive it.
我觉得会被炒作一个礼拜 然后风暴就会过了…
I think it'll be a big deal for about a week, and then the storm will pass...
我是说我们俩
I'm talking about you and me.
“候选人毁于讲稿作者之女友”
"Candidate Brought Down by Speechwriter's GirIfriend."
-拜托 -我只是在做我的工作
-Come on. -I'm just doing my job.
我第一次时并没有尽责
I didn't do it the first time around.
就算我不写也会有人写
And if I didn't write this, somebody else would.
让他们写
Let them.
嘿，  别交上去，  好吗？
Hey, don't hand this in, okay?
你已经交了
You already did.
亚瑟先生…
Mr. Arthur...
(CHATTERING)
好的
ARTHUR: Yeah, sure.
我真的很喜欢夏曼
I really liked Summer.
我真不敢相信她竟然如此…
I can't believe she turned out to be such a...
-让人心碎？ -不
-Heartbreaker? -No.
投机者？背叛…
-Opportunist? Double-crossing... -Uh-uh.
-贱人 -玛雅
-Bitch. -Maya.
她怎么能这样对你？
How could she do that to you?
就如她所说，  她要是不写 也会有别人去写
It's like she said. If she didn't write it, someone else would have.
而且那是事实
And it was the truth.
她有吗？她让你心碎吗？
So did she? Did she break it?
什么？
What?
文章登出后呢？
What happened when the article came out?
《纽约日报》：  他出局了！
你搞砸了，老兄，  你真的搞砸了
You screwed up, man. You really screwed up.
省省吧，  我现在不想听你说教
Please save it. I don't need to hear this right now.
等我搞清楚这件事 会带给我什么教训时
Whenever I figure out whatever I'm supposed to learn from all this,
-我会通知你的 -我迫不及待
-I'll write you a letter! -Yeah, can't wait.
我失去了女友、工作、朋友
So I lost my girl, I lost my job, and I lost my friend.
有好长一段时间，  一切仿佛都不重要
And for a long time, nothing seemed to matter.
但世上有问题的不只是我
But I wasn't the only one with problems.
我与那女人之间没有性关系
I did not have sexual relations with that woman,
陆文斯基小姐
Miss Lewinsky.
我从未要求别人撒谎
I never told anybody to lie.
-喂？ -你在看吗？
-Hello? -Are you watching?
这些指控是错误的
These allegations are false.
艾波？
April?
嗯，  是艾波？你以为是谁？ 你到底有没有在看？
Yeah, April. Who'd you think it was? Are you watching or not?
当然在看
Of course I'm watching.
你觉得他做了吧？
You think he did it, don't you?
我不用觉得，  我知道 你看她的照片，  我爱她
I don't think, I know. Look at the picture of her. I love her.
她超像他的型
She's so his type.
你为什么这么久才回我电话，  小红？
So, what took you so long to finally call me back there, red?
我还以为我失去你了
I thought I lost you.
-感觉好像好几年了 -我现在不是打给你了吗？
-Feels like years. -I'm calling you now, aren't I?
嗯
Yeah.
你好吗？都在做些什么？
How are you? What's doing?
我多了个室友，  奥莉微雅
I got a new roommate, Olivia.
我在书店做事
And I'm working at a bookstore.
本书属于芭芭拉贝克 夏绿蒂白朗特著《简爱》
但我一直在想要不要回去念书
But I've been thinking about going back to school.
酷
Cool.
嘿，  我有说我痛恨我的工作吗？
Hey, did I tell you that I hate my job?
我以前好爱我的工作 但我现在觉得自己像个骗子
I used to love what I do, and now I feel like a complete hack.
海约先生：抱歉，  但这本《简爱》首页并没有题词，  需要继续找吗？
-你交女朋友了吗？ -我？我交…不，  完全没有
-Are you seeing anyone? -Me? Am I... No, no. Absolutely not.
我从柯林顿连任后就没做过了
In fact, I haven't had sex since Clinton was re-elected.
何必费事呢？他将全国的额度都包了
Why bother? He's having enough sex for the entire country.
别这么缺德
Easy. Easy now.
嘿，  或许你该跟随他的脚步 去勾引实习生
Hey, maybe you should follow his lead and seduce an intern.
你提到这还真巧
You know, it's funny that you should mention that.
上礼拜才来了个很正的实习生
There's a fetching young intern who just started a week ago.
很好，  约她出去啊
Great. Ask her out.
我确实该，  是吗？
I should, shouldn't I?
但我想应该不会吧，  我不想只是玩玩
But I don't think I will. You see, I don't want a fling.
我要的是真爱
I want the real deal.
别管什么真爱了，  真爱由不得你去找 它自己会找上门
Forget about the real deal. You don't find it, it finds you.
什么意思？我不懂这其中的意思
What does that mean? I don't know what that means.
意思就是等你年纪到了并准备好时
It means that you get to a certain age and then you're ready.
就是你准备好生孩子或是给承诺 或者是…
You know, you're ready for kids or a commitment or, you know...
-先生 -…背房贷
-Sir. -...a mortgage.
-位子准备好了 -谢谢
-Table’s ready. Okay. -Thanks.
懂吗？
You know what I mean?
当时跟你在一起的人 就是你的真命天子
And the person that you're with then, they become the one.
你的意思是不是人的问题 而是时机罗？
So you're saying it's not who, but it's when.
-正是 -好吧
-Exactly. -Okay. All right.
所以从未有个男的让你觉得 “就是这个
So there's never been a guy, ever, that made you think, "This is it.
“就是他了，  他是真命天子”
"This is him. This is the one."
没有
No.
好，  那你为什么不出去玩呢？
Okay, then why aren't you out there, you know, enjoying yourself?
我有啊
I am.
-你有？ -对
-You are? -Yes.
我现在与一个叫凯文的约会
Right now I'm seeing this guy, Kevin.
-凯文 -凯文
-Kevin. -Kevin.
凯文他妈的是谁啊？
Who the hell's Kevin?
哪来的…你怎么从来没提过他？
Where did... How come you never, you know, mentioned anything about him?
我现在不是在提
I'm mentioning him now.
天啊！他们这有新鲜的薄荷茶 我最爱薄荷茶了
Oh, God! They have fresh mint tea. I love fresh mint tea.
我爱啤酒
I love beer.
那要看“是”的定义为何了
It depends upon what the meaning of the word "is" is.
若意思是“是没有” 这句话完全的真实
If it means "there is none" that is a completely true statement.
(BEEPS)
嘿，  是艾波
(ON ANSWERING MACHINE) Hey, this is April.
我要跟你谈谈你生日的事，  打给我
I want to talk to you about your birthday. Call me.
(BEEPS)
哈罗，  希望这是对的号码 听起来像是你的声音
Hello. I hope this is the right number. It sounds like you.
我是艾蜜莉！
It's Emily!
(LAUGHS)
我人在纽约，  我在想
I'm in New York, and I was thinking
或许我们可以喝杯咖啡、叙叙旧
maybe we could get a cup of coffee and catch up.
我的号码是…
My number...
(BEEPS)
嘿，  是艾波，  我还是需要跟你聊 请回电
Hey, it's April. I still need to talk to you. Please call me back.
别逼我过去扁你
I mean, don't make me come over there and hurt you.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
好啦，  我来了
Okay, I'm coming!
天啊，  来了
God, I'm coming.
嗯，  知道了
Yeah, I get it.
你在里面干嘛？
What are you doing in there?
-你就穿这样？ -什么？
-Is this what you're wearing? -What?
是你的生日派对，  大家都在等你
It's your birthday party. Everybody is waiting for you.
天啊
Oh, Christ.
五分钟，  好吗？五…
Five minutes, okay? Five...
(CRASHING)
-我摔倒了 -没事吧？
- I'm down. -Are you okay?
嗯，  我只需要躺一下
Yeah. I just need to lie here for a sec.
(GROANS)
看来你有在吃面
I see you've been eating noodles.
嘿，  大家，  他到了！
Hey, everybody, he's here!
(ALL CHEERING)
谢了
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
我的天！我没想到你也来了！
Oh, my God! I didn't think you'd be here!
怎么能错过你生日 我们特地从华府赶来的
I couldn’t miss your birthday. We came all the way up from Washington.
生日快乐，  帅哥
Happy birthday, gorgeous.
这可是个漂亮的女人
That is a beautiful woman right there.
你曾有机会的
You had your chance, pal.
海约
Hayes.
过来
Come on.
(RUSSELL LAUGHING)
-见到你真好 -嗯，  你看来…
-It's great to see you. -Yeah. You look...
像游民，  我知道
Homeless, I know.
-凯莉呢？ -她在那边
-Where's Kelly? -She's right over there.
这是她在生宝宝后第一次出来玩
It's her first night out since the baby was born.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
伊朗军售、石油换武器，  没问题
Iran-Contra. Arms for oil, no problem.
但一点点“嘴上功夫”就面临弹劾
But a little "oralness" and you're headed for impeachment.
-不谈政治 -或许他该被弹劾
-No politics! -Maybe he should be impeached.
等等、等等！那话是他说的吗？
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait! Did he say that?
-为什么不该？我相信他，  我们都是 -你爱他
-Why not? I put my faith in him. We all did. -You love him.
我以为他跟其他那些小丑不同
I thought he was gonna be different than the other jokers,
但他连“是”这个字都无法定义
but this guy, he can't even define the word "is."
要是他们给他像“事实”这种字呢？
What happens if they give him one of the hard words, like "truth"?
-我还是会选他 -想都不用想
-I'd vote for him again. -In a heartbeat.
威尔很好玩
Will's a lot of fun.
嗯，  不如我们将澡缸放满水 然后再将烤面包机丢进去
Yeah, let's fill up the tub and drop in a toaster.
应该很好玩吧
That should be a good time.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
祝亲爱的威尔生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Will
-他呢？威尔呢？ -不知道，  刚刚还在跟他说话
-Where is he? Where's Will? -I don't know. I was just talking to him.
你错过了你的生日蛋糕
You missed your birthday cake.
Uh-oh.
-是我烤的 -你烤的
And I baked it. -You baked it.
你还记得那首歌吗？
Do you remember that song?
在你的公寓？
In your apartment?
以朋友的身分前来
Come as you are, as a friend
以宿敌
As a known enemy
-是“记忆”不是“宿敌” -我知道、我知道、我知道
-"Memory," not "enemy." -I know, I know, I know.
-有人喝多了 -我没有
-Somebody had too much to drink. -No, I didn't.
我没有、我没有、我没有
I didn't, I didn't. I didn't.
-有，  你有 -我有
-Yes, you did. -I did.
-天啊，  你好美 -谢谢
-God, you're beautiful. -Thank you.
什么？
What?
问题是…
The thing is...
(CLEARS THROAT)
问题是…
The thing is...
我喜欢你
Is that I like you.
我一直都喜欢你
I've always liked you.
“喜欢”
"Like."
好可悲、好逊的字眼
That's pathetic. It's so puny.
另一方面，  “爱”…
"Love" on the other hand...
听到这种字眼你一定会吓跑
You'd run away from a word like that.
我爱你
I love you.
艾波，  我爱上你了
I'm in love with you, April.
-你为何没告诉过我？ -拜托
-Why didn't you ever tell me? -Come on.
你知道我为什么没跟你说 你根本不会看上我
You know exactly why I never told you. You'd never be interested in me.
你这白痴
You're an idiot.
-住手 -什么？
-Stop. -What?
-不是这样 -怎样？
-Not like this. -Like what?
你看你，  威尔，  你一团糟
Look at you, Will, you're a mess.
你好好的时候为什么不跟我说？
Why couldn’t you have told me when you had your shit together?
-我很好啊 -你一团乱
-My shit is together. -Your shit is a mess.
你一团乱
You're a mess.
我一团乱？
My shit is a mess?
艾波，  从你口中听到这句还真有趣
That's interesting, coming from you, April.
你想做什么都可以，  但却在书店打工
You could do anything on earth, and you work in a bookstore.
是怎样？
What's that all about?
最起码我试过了，  我出去闯过了
At least I tried. I went out there and I tried.
我只是以朋友的身分 我发誓是以朋友的身分
Look, I'm just saying this as a friend, and I swear, it's just as a friend,
或许你该去寻求些咨询
but maybe you should go out there and, you know, get some help.
去参加复健或重建人生之类的
Go to rehab or life rehab or something like that.
我不清楚是否有这种东西 但若有的话…
I don't even know if they have that sort of thing, but if they did...
好
Okay.
…非常的适合你
...you know, you could be a prime candidate for that.
-我该去“重建人生”？ -嗯
-I should go to "life rehab"? -Yeah.
滚开我的前院！
Get off my front porch!
艾波？
April?
(BOTTLE SHATTERS)
你说的对
You're right.
是很复杂，  对吗？
It is complicated, isn't it?
你爱艾波，  她曾爱过卢卡斯
I mean, you're in love with April, who used to be in love with Lucas,
后来爱上你时，  你却爱夏曼
and then she fell in love with you, but you were in love with Summer,
她却一直爱著汉普顿
who was always really in love with Hampton.
你现在爱上艾波时，  她又爱凯文
And now that you're in love with April, she's in love with Kevin.
却没有人爱你
And no one's in love with you.
很复杂
That's complicated.
对
Yep.
然后呢？
Then what happened?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
夏绿蒂白朗特著《简爱》
《简爱》，  蓝灯书屋出版，  1943年
Jane Eyre, Random House, 1943.
这版很漂亮，  以美丽的封面著名
It's a beautiful edition, known for the cover illustration.
但里面的题词很美，  是书中的句子
But there's a really nice dedication inside, with a quote from the book.
“给我的女儿，  艾波 “人类的心充满著隐藏的宝藏
"To my darling daughter, April. 'The human heart has hidden treasures
-“未说的秘密与未打破的沉默中” -“  “未打破的沉默中
-"'In secret kept, in silence sealed..."' - "'In silence sealed
“  “那些想法、希望、梦想、快乐
"'The thoughts, the hopes the dreams, the pleasures
“  “其魔法将因透露而破解”
"'Whose charms were broken if revealed'
“爱你的父亲赠”
"From your loving father."
-嗨，  奥莉微雅 -嗨，  威尔
-Hi, Olivia. -Hi, Will.
-你好吗？ -好
-How you been? -Good.
我很久没听到你那冗长的道歉了
I haven't heard any of your long sorry messages in a while.
它们很棒吧？真是抱歉
Those were delightful, weren't they? Sorry about that.
-艾波在吗？ -不，  她去上课
-April here? -No, she's at school.
-上课？ -嗯
-School? -Yeah.
-她在纽约大学念硕士班 -很好，  哗
-She started grad school at NYU. -Great. Wow.
-你若要等她的话，  她很快就回来了 -好啊
-If you want to wait, she'll be home soon. -I'd love to.
自己坐，  我得填完这张表格
Make yourself comfortable. I have to finish this application I'm writing.
-祝你好运 -谢了
-Good luck. -Thanks.
(SIGHS)
嘿
Hey.
你好吗？
How you doing?
我是凯文
Kevin.
威尔海约
Will Hayes.
我只是在等艾波
I'm just waiting for April.
你是她前阵子提的凯文吗？
Are you the same Kevin that she mentioned a while back?
(PHONE RINGING)
希望是罗，  除非她是在收集叫凯文的
I hope so. Unless she's collecting Kevins.
凯文，  电话！
OLIVIA: Kevin, phone!
我满确定我是唯一跟她同居的凯文
Anyway, I'm pretty sure I am the only Kevin who's actually living with her.
你知道你要什么了吗？
Do you know what you want yet?
-不 -不？
-No. -WAITRESS: No?
威尔？
Will?
威廉海约？
William Hayes?
天啊
God.
-是你！ -夏曼
-It is! -Summer.
你好美
You look beautiful.
不管你信不信，  我一直想打给你
Believe it or not, I've been meaning to call you.
-我怀孕了 -你什么？
-I'm pregnant. -You're what?
-真的？ -你相信吗？
-Really? -Can you believe it?
-请坐下，恭喜你 -谢谢、谢谢
-Please, sit. Congratulations. -Thanks. Thanks.
是哪个幸运的家伙？
Who's the lucky guy?
-山姆诺斯 -喔
-Sam Knowles. -Okay.
但他基本上已经出局了
But he's basically out of the picture.
-他没上榜喔？ -嗯
-He didn't make the cut, huh? -Yeah.
我也不需要男人，  一直都不是很需要
Well, I don't need a guy. I never really did.
你应该算是最亲密的吧
You were about the closest I ever got.
真的，  我跟你在一起时曾想过 “就是他了”
No, really, when I was with you, I thought, "This is it."
但我搞砸了
But I screwed it up.
-你没有 -我有，  绝对有
-No, you didn't. -I did. I so did.
听著
Listen,
我星期天要办个小聚会
I'm having a little party Sunday.
-我要你来 -天啊
-I want you to come. -Oh, boy.
下午四点，  不准不到
4:00. No excuses.
(SIGHING)
你要来吗？拜托嘛？
Will you come? Please?
我看看赶不赶得上
You know, I'll see if I can make it.
-我很希望你来 -我会到的
-I really want you to. -I'll make it.
我想跟被我伤害过的人言归于好
I want to make amends with anyone I ever hurt.
我估计要花上九个月
And I figure it'll take about nine months,
时间上刚好
which is perfect timing.
-她要走了，  再见 -再见
-And she's off. Bye. -Bye-bye.
威廉海约
William Hayes.
-爸，  或许这主意不是很好 -什么？
-Dad, maybe this wasn't such a good idea. - What?
跟我说这故事，  这爱情悬疑故事
Telling me this story, this mystery love story.
-要是我不喜欢我妈怎么办？ -你当然会喜欢你妈
-What if I don't like who my mom is? -Of course you'll like who your mom is.
你不用等太久，  因为当晚…
And you don't have to wait long to find out, because that very night...
是夏曼，  对不对？而你不是我生父
It's Summer, isn't it? And you're not my father.
难怪你不想跟她在一起
No wonder you didn't want to be with her.
放轻松点，玛雅，  这只是个故事
Take it easy, Maya. It's just a story.
而且有快乐的结局
And this one has a happy ending.
怎么会有快乐结局？
How does it have a happy ending?
你跟我妈，  不管她是谁 你们要离婚了
You and my mom, whoever she is, you're getting divorced.
有什么好快乐的？
What's the happy in that?
好吧，  你知道吗？我们该停了
Okay, you know what? I think we should stop now.
不！
No!
来杯茶好吗？
Then how about a nice cup of tea?
你想的话，  我们继续讲故事，  如何？
If you want, I'll still continue with the story. Does that sound good?
-玛雅？ -好
-Maya? -Okay.
爸？
Dad?
我真不敢相信你又抽烟又喝酒 还那么随便
I can't believe you smoked and drank and were such a slut.
但我还是爱你
But I still love you.
(SIGHS)
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
谢了
Thanks.
好的、好的
All right. All right.
不、不，  先别吃，要先到我们的板凳
No, no. Don't eat it yet! Not till we get to our bench.
你心情不错
You're in a good mood.
我想我从故事中发现了我妈是谁
Well, I think I discovered who my mom is in the story.
-真的？ -真的
-Really? -Really.
-是谁？ -不告诉你
-Well, who is it? -Not telling.
我们最后一次见到威廉海约时
So the last time we saw William Hayes,
他刚发现他的至爱，  艾波霍夫曼
he had just discovered that the woman he truly loved, April Hoffman,
爱上了别人
was in love with another man.
(WILLIAM GASPS)
我知道，很耸动
I know. Shocking.
在这期间，  他接受了邀约
Meanwhile, he accepted an invitation
去他前女友夏曼哈德尼家
to the home of his ex-girlfriend, Summer Hartley,
她若真是我妈，  我就逃去加拿大
who, if she does turn out to be my mother, I'm running away to Canada.
我不是说笑
I'm not kidding.
-他去年走了 -嗯
-He died last year. -Yeah.
-你听说了？ -我在《纽约时报》上有看到
-You heard? -I read about it in The Times.
-嗯 -嗯
-Yeah. -Yeah.
-天啊，  在办公室里，  心脏病吗？ -嗯
-God. Died in his office. Heart attack? -Yeah.
我一直以为他会走得很戏剧性
I always imagined that he'd make a more theatrical exit.
他们没说他当时 跟系主任的女儿在沙发上
What they didn't say was he was on the couch with the dean's daughter.
-老天 -开玩笑的
-Jesus. -I'm kidding.
事实上他是一个人 好几个小时后才被工友发现
Actually, he was completely alone and it was hours before the janitor found him.
-要喝点什么？ -抱歉
-You want a drink? -I'm sorry.
-你一定很想念他 -我是啊
-You must miss him. -I do, yeah.
这是给你的
These are for you.
-喔，  威尔 -嗯
-Oh, Will. -Yeah.
好美
They're beautiful.
你也是
So are you.
-夏曼 -威尔
-Summer. -Will.
别闹我
Don't mess with me.
我知道你想要干嘛
I can see where you're going with this.
再过一会，  你就会说句迷死人的话
In a second, you're gonna say something impossibly charming.
-真的？ -嗯，  会很棒
-Really? -Yeah. It's gonna be great.
然后你会完全迷倒我 我们都知道结局会是什么
And then you're gonna sweep me off my feet and we all know where that's going.
-女孩难道就不能想念男孩吗？ -你也知道没好下场
-Can't a girl miss a guy? -And you know that's gonna end badly.
她可以
Yeah, she can,
但我真的没时间承受那种痛
but I just don't really have time for the pain.
-不如就略过这些吧？ -好
-So let's just skip all that, why don't we? -Okay.
很公平
Fair enough.
能做朋友吗？
Can we be friends?
-好！好 -好
-Yeah! Yeah. -Yeah.
-一言为定？好 -就这样，  好
-Shake on it? Okay. -Let's do that. All right.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我想让你见个人
There's someone here I want you to meet.
嗯，  跟我来
Yeah. Come with me.
是我的旧爱
They're an old flame of mine,
我觉得你们俩应该很聊得来
and I think you guys are really gonna, you know, hit it off.
艾蜜莉
Emily.
我把这些插起来
I'm gonna put these in some water.
-你看来… -你看来…
-You look... -You look...
(EMILY CHUCKLING)
你看来很好
You look great.
-你怎么在纽约？ -我住在这
-Why are you in New York? -I live here.
我在市政府教育部做事
I took a job with the city education department.
-我有打给你 -我知道
-I called you. -I know.
-我一直想回你 -骗子
-I've been meaning to call you back. -Liar.
-我弄丢了你的号码 -当然
-I had lost your number. -Of course.
-是真的，  你知道吗？ -威尔…
-No, it's true. You know what? -Will...
好吧，现在就给我你的电话
Okay, give me your number, right now.
我马上输入我的手机里 这样就永远不会掉了，  好吗？
I'm gonna put it in my cell phone, and that way I'm never gonna lose it, okay?
我的号码是212-664-7665
My number is 212-664-7665.
6、6、5，  你看？我输入了 现在就不会掉了
Six, six, five. See? Now I got it. And I'm never gonna lose it again.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-没关系，  接啊 -抱歉
-Oh, no, go ahead, go ahead. -Sorry.
-喂 -喂，  我是威尔
-Hello. -Hey, it's Will.
我很抱歉弄掉你的电话
I'm really sorry I lost your number.
我刚刚突然有好奇怪的画面闪过
I just had the weirdest flash of a whole life,
从未发生的画面
one that never, ever happened.
我们怎么了？
What did happen to us?
你跟我的室友上床
-You slept with my roommate. -Oh!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没记错的话 是我的“计划”不是吗？
If I remember correctly, I believe it was my "plan," wasn't it?
-那计划，  还记得吗？ -对，  计划
-The plan. Remember that? -Yes, the plan.
谁这样说话？
Who talks like that?
不，  不是计划 我只是害怕你与你的梦想
No, it wasn't the plan. I was scared of you and your dreams,
然而我们分手后，  我好迷失
and then after we broke up, I just felt lost.
我还是感到很迷失，  尤其在谈感情时
I still feel pretty lost, especially when it comes to relationships.
嗯
Yeah.
嗯，  我也…我也是
Yeah, I've been... Me, too.
你有没有想过
Did you ever think
或许我们需要的 只是一个不同的计划？
that maybe we just needed a different plan?
等等！停止！倒回去
Wait! Stop! Stop right there. Now, go back.
(REWINDING)
好，  停，  慢速往前
Okay, stop. Now go forward, slowly.
就是这里
Now here it comes.
那里！就是那里！
There! Right there!
就是那个！ 我就是因为那个才猜到的！
That's it! That's how I figured it out!
我每次不开心时妈都会那样做
That's what Mom does when I'm upset.
她会摸摸我的头发，要我变得很棒
She fluffs up my hair and tells me to be brilliant
或是像太阳一样耀眼 每次都让我觉得好多了
or shine like the sun, and it always makes me feel better.
-听来像是个好母亲 -她是很棒的母亲
-Sounds like a great mom. -She is a great mom.
所以你百分百确定艾蜜莉 就是现在朝我们走过来
So you're absolutely positive, 100%, that Emily is the very same woman
的那个女人？
walking toward us right now?
绝对是
Absolutely.
是吗？
Is it?
-妈！妈！ -嘿！
-Mom! Mom! -Hey!
我好高兴是你
I'm so glad it's you.
-不然是谁？ -谁都不是
-Well, who else would it be? -Nobody.
-早安，  威尔 -嘿，  莎拉
-Good morning, Will. -Hey, Sarah.
妈，  爸可以跟我们一起来吗？
Mom, can Dad come with us to the zoo?
可以啊，  若爸爸想来的话
Yeah, if Dad wants to come, sure.
我最喜欢动物园了，  我们去动物园吧
You know, I love the zoo. Let's go to the zoo.
-妈，  你猜怎么样？ -怎样？
-Guess what, Mom? - What?
我们昨天在学校学性教育
We learned all about sexual intercourse at school yesterday.
-真的？ -真的
-Really? -Really.
真的
Really.
(PENGUINS CALLING)
我爱企鹅
I love penguins.
我也是
Me, too.
Me, three.
你们知道企鹅是终身配偶吗？
Did you know that penguins mate for life?
虽然摩纳老师跟我们说
Although, Mr. Monell told us
有时企鹅丈夫与企鹅妻子会因为
that sometimes the husband and wife penguins get separated
它们的头痛模式而分开
'cause of their migraine patterns.
-是迁徙 -是迁徙
-Migratory. -Migratory.
它们有时一分开就好几年 但永远都找得到对方
Well, sometimes they're apart for years, but they almost always find each other.
你们知道企鹅夫妻
Do you know what the husband and wife penguins do
找到对方后会做什么吗？
after they find each other after all that time?
会将头仰起
Throw back their heads,
拍著翅膀大声唱歌！
flap their flippers and sing as loud as they can!
(IMITATING PENGUIN CALLS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
好的，  小鬼头，  走吧！
Okay. All right, munchkin. Let's go!
嘿，  小妖怪，  今天很好玩 我们星期三见，  好吗？
Hey, monster, that was fun today. I'll see you on Wednesday, okay?
(BELLS RINGING)
再见罗
See you later.
爸！
Dad!
-谢谢你把故事说给我听 -不客气
-Thanks for telling me the story. -You're welcome.
-我忘了告诉你快乐的结局了 -是什么？
-I forgot to tell you the happy ending. -What is it?
你啊
You.
(SOBBING)
-嘿，  我爱你 -我也爱你
-Hey, I love you. -I love you, too.
去找你妈了，  好吗？好了，  再见
Go catch up to your mom, okay? All right, bye.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
好吗？
Yeah?
(SNIFFS)
总统先生！嘿，  总统先生！
Mr. President! Hey, Mr. President!
威尔海约 我在92年竞选时替你做过事
Will Hayes, I worked on the '92 campaign.
(EXHALES)
国际特赦组织美国总会
嗨，  我找艾波
Hi. I'm looking for April.
记得查他们有没有法律代表，  好吗？
Check that they have legal representation, okay?
-好 -多谢，  约翰
-Right. -Thanks, John.
(LAUGHING)
我不敢相信你在做这个
I can't believe you're doing this.
-很棒 -谢谢
-This is great. -Thanks.
-还抽烟？ -戒了
-Still smoking? -I quit.
-我也是，  还住在同样的公寓？ -搬到布鲁克林
-Me, too. Still live in the same loft? -Living in Brooklyn.
永远走在时代尖端
AIways on the cutting edge.
-有男友吗？ -目前没有，  你呢？
-Dating? -Not at present. You?
-我离婚了 -我知道
-(WHISPERS) I got divorced. -I know.
我听说了，很抱歉
I heard. I'm so sorry.
为什么？
Why?
你老是说人们太高估婚姻
You always said marriage was overrated.
是啊，  你从来就不听我的 每次都在买戒指
Yeah, and you never listened to me. You were always with the rings.
-所以你跟凯文才没有… -天啊，  凯文，  不，  凯文…
-Is that why you and Kevin never... -Oh, God, Kevin. No. Kevin...
跟凯文总是少了什么
Something always seemed to be missing with Kevin.
我不知道
I don't know.
很怪，  但总是不太对，  懂吗？
It's weird. It was never quite right. You know?
嗯
Yeah.
-见到你真好 -你也是
-It's good to see you. -You, too.
我有东西给你
I have something for you.
(EXCLAIMING)
(APRIL CRYING)
很谢谢你
Thank you so much.
你怎么找到的？ 我是说，  你在哪找到的？
How did you find it? I mean, where did you find it?
说来话长
That's the difficult part to explain.
这听起来会很糟
This is gonna sound bad.
我找到很久了
I've had it for a while.
多久？
How long?
好几年
Years.
很多年了
Many years.
我是想…
I meant to...
我是打算要给你，  我想要给你
I meant to give it to you. I wanted to give it to you.
只是…
I just...
送不出手，  而我也不知道为什么
I couldn’t. And I don't know why.
我有次带过去，  我试了，  凯文也在…
I dropped it off once. I mean, I tried. Kevin was there and...
嘿，  没有藉口，  我很抱歉
Hey, there is no excuse, and I'm sorry.
不可原谅
It's inexcusable.
-你该走了，  威尔 -艾波？
-I think you should go, Will. -April?
你该走了
I think you should go.
你没给她？这么久都没给她？
You never gave it to her? After all that time?
-我知道 -那是她爸爸给她的
- I know. I know. -But it was from her dad.
我知道、我知道
I know. I know.
然后你就这样走了？
And then you just left?
没错
Yep.
为什么除了她之外其他人都化名？
How come you changed all the names except hers?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
故事里妈妈成了艾蜜莉
In the story, you know, like Mom became Emily,
夏曼就是帮杂志社写报导 那个叫娜塔莎的女人
and Summer's that Natasha lady who writes for that magazine.
但你没有改艾波的名字，  为什么？
But you didn't change April’s name. Why?
你为什么对这些这么感兴趣？
Why are you so concerned with all of this anyway?
因为我希望你快乐
Because I want you to be happy.
你知道
You know,
我很快乐
I'm happy.
相信我，  爸，  你不快乐
Trust me, Dad. You're not happy.
去穿大衣
Put your coat on.
-计程车 -计程车
-Taxi! -Taxi!
她说跟凯文少了什么
She said something was missing with Kevin,
意思就是跟你却没有缺少
which means it might not be missing with you,
-这样是好事，  对吗？ -可能吧
-which is good news, right? -CouId be.
可能吧
CouId be.
你知道一年里 有35个人跳布鲁克林桥吗？
Did you know that 35 people try to jump off the Brooklyn Bridge each year?
大多是因为心碎
Most because of broken hearts.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
(BUZZING)
-哈罗 -嘿，  嗨
- Hello. -Hey. Hi.
是我，  威尔
It's me, Will.
(GASPS)
艾波？
April?
你来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
Uh...
跟她说啊
Go on, tell her.
那是谁？
Who's that?
那是我的女儿，玛雅
That would be my daughter, Maya.
这样不算是做弊吗？带你女儿来？
That's kind of cheating, isn't it? Bringing your daughter?
现在我该怎么办？
What am I supposed to do now?
你可以放我们进去啊
Well, you could let us in.
我想她不会让我们进去了
I don't think she's gonna let us in.
(EXHALES)
我觉得你错了
I think you're wrong.
来，  我们走吧
Come on, let's go. Let's go.
再等一下，  她会让我们进去的
A little while longer. She's going to let us in.
好的，  小鬼头，  这样吧
Okay, kiddo, here's the deal.
我数到30，  好吗？
I'm gonna count to 30, okay?
若她不开门，  我们就回家了
And if she doesn't let us in, we're gonna go home,
然后以后都别再提起这件事
and we're never gonna talk about this again.
-协议达成吗？ -嗯
-DeaI? -Yeah.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
-1、2、3… -1、2、3…
-One, two, three... -One, two, three...
-…4、5、6… -…4、5、6…
-...four, five, six... -...four, five, six...
-…14、15、16、17… -…14、15、16、17…
-... 14, 15, 16, 17... -... 14, 15, 16, 17...
她要是让我们进去 你要像跟我说的一样把故事讲给她听
If she lets us in, tell her the story like you told me.
-这样她就会知道了 -知道什么？
-And then she'll know. - Know what?
我不会解释，  反正她就会懂了
I can't explain. She'll just know.
-…25、26、27… -…25、26、27…
-...25, 26, 27... -...25, 26, 27...
-29 -29
-Twenty-nine. -Twenty-nine.
29又四分之一
Twenty-nine and a quarter.
29又二分之一
Twenty-nine and a half.
29又四分之三
Twenty-nine and three-quarters.
再来呢？
What comes after that?
该走了
Time to go.
但不应该是这样的
But this wasn't what was supposed to have happened.
-我知道 -我真的以为
-I know. -I really thought
她在对讲机听到我们的对话 就会放我们进去
she would have heard through the intercom and let us in,
或是跑下楼说…
or run down the stairs and say...
什么故事？
What story?
-我将书留下… -怎样？
-I kept the book... -Yeah?
…是因为那是我仅有的属于你的东西
...because it was the only thing that I had left of you.
-你一定是玛雅 -你一定是艾波
-You must be Maya. -You must be April.
然后呢？
So what happens now?
你请我们进去 然后我们说故事给你听
You invite us inside, and we tell you the story.
好
Okay.
(UPBEAT FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)